<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ekoparty2020 on OSU Security Club</title><link>https://osusec.org/tags/ekoparty2020/</link><description>Recent content in ekoparty2020 on OSU Security Club</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://osusec.org/tags/ekoparty2020/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>EkoPartyCTF - Docs</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/ekopartyctf-docs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/ekopartyctf-docs/</guid><description>EkoParty CTF 2020 Git 2
Prompt Exact prompt has been forgotten. Linked to this GitHub repo
Solution As I mentioned in the writeup for leak, I was in a very githubby mindset when I started this challenge. For that reason, I solved this challenge first.
A quick inspection of the repo shows that it features an accidentally committed SSH private key and matching public key. I copied the text of these out of the commit log, and into chall and chall.</description></item><item><title>EkoPartyCTF - Env</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/ekopartyctf-env/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/ekopartyctf-env/</guid><description>EkoParty CTF 2020 Git 3
Prompt Not too sure of the original prompt, however I did not need it.
Solution After the second part of the git challenge saga, we have gotten a new repository with some new github actions. We know, before analyzing these however, that:
Issues filed to the ekolabs repo will be ‘moved’ to the ekoparty-internal repo. We control content in the submitted issues, and this is copied to the new issues in ekoparty-internal repo.</description></item><item><title>EkoPartyCTF - Leak</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/ekopartyctf-leak/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/ekopartyctf-leak/</guid><description>EkoParty CTF 2020 Git 1
Prompt Exact prompt has been forgotten. Linked to this GitHub repo
Solution This solution was quite obscure, as I approached this challenge in a github mindset, not a ctf::misc one. In light of this, I solved the second challenge first 😛
When I got on to solving this one, it took me several runs through the full commit history of the repo before seeing this:</description></item></channel></rss>