<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Meeting Notes on OSU Security Club</title><link>https://osusec.org/categories/meeting-notes/</link><description>Recent content in Meeting Notes on OSU Security Club</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 12:04:17 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://osusec.org/categories/meeting-notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Meeting 10/18/23</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-10-18-23/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 12:04:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-10-18-23/</guid><description>Ni Haowdy!
Last night, we hosted Dr. Kelsey Fulton of the Colorado School of Mines. They talked about their research into the why and the how that software developers introduce security vulnerabilities into their code, and some potential solutions for it. We had some great conversations about the attitudes in software development spaces and how we might be able to change that for the future. Please reach out to Dr. Fulton if you are interested in working with them on further research!</description></item><item><title>Meeting 10/11/23</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-10-11-23/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2023 13:41:15 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-10-11-23/</guid><description>Howdy hackers!
Last night, we had the fantastic Jonathan Keller give a talk about how he used his pwn skills in order to get a world record in a Tool Assisted Speedrun of Super Metroid! Thank you everyone who showed up :) He discussed the game&amp;rsquo;s internal mechanics, how the exploit works, and his experience developing the real-world exploit as a cybersecurity student and as someone who enjoys retro games.</description></item><item><title>Meeting 10/04/23</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-10-04-23/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 14:44:22 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-10-04-23/</guid><description>Howdy hackers!
Thanks for showing up last night, and staying flexible with us! I know we weren&amp;rsquo;t able to host the meeting we wanted at the last minute, but hopefully you got to enjoy some memes, learn about the club, and possibly pick a lock for the first time! We hope to see you again in more meetings throughout the term. Please feel free to reach out to any officer if you have questions or need help!</description></item><item><title>Meeting Notes 11/09</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-11-09/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-11-09/</guid><description>Howdy hackers! Last night, I covered cybersecurity in software development. I talked about how you can incorporate security into each stage of the Software Development Lifecycle, some examples of how that has gone wrong in real life software projects, and the different mitigations that have come about in an effort to control memory corruption attacks (an example of improper input handling).
The slides for the meeting are available here (ONID required): https://docs.</description></item><item><title>Meeting Notes 11/02</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-11-02/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-11-02/</guid><description>Howdy hackers! Welcome to the second half of Fall term! Tonight we hosted NetSPI: Senior Director Karl Fosaaen and Security Consultant (and former club member) Michael Jereza. They walked us through penetration testing as a career, what work is like at NetSPI, their NetSPI University program, and some entertaining stories from their pentesting work! We hope you had fun and walked away with an enthusiasm for pentesting. If you enjoyed this, definitely think about getting involved with our CPTC team!</description></item><item><title>Meeting Notes 10/19</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-10-19/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-10-19/</guid><description>Howdy hackers! Hope your week 4 is going well. Tonight Cameron introduced Reversed Engineering (“Rev”) challenges and how to pwn them. Rev and pwn challenges are a staple of CTF competitions, and we covered a few of the most critical tools in your arsenal for approaching them. We also walked you through an introductory pwn challenge called rev01 that is hosted on our CTF Practice Range. We hope you were able to walk away with some new skills.</description></item><item><title>Meeting Notes 10/12</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-10-12/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-10-12/</guid><description>Howdy hackers! Thanks to everyone who showed up tonight! Tonight we introduced the NSA Codebreaker Challenge, and held a work party. Hopefully you were able to make some progress on Tasks in a focused environment and get free dinner! We covered previous year’s Codebreaker themes, the NSA’s mission and how that inspires the Challenge, and introduced the different tools that the NSA recommends to approach the Challenge with.
The slides for the meeting are available here (ONID required): https://docs.</description></item><item><title>Meeting Notes 10/05</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-10-05/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-10-05/</guid><description>Howdy hackers! Thanks to everyone who showed up, and we hope it was enjoyable and informative! Tonight we introduced Cyber Defense Competitions. We covered some of the skills and areas you would learn by playing in a CDC, what makes them fun, and the career advantages of getting involved in them!
The slides for the meeting are available here: [https://www.osusec.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/2022-10-05-Intro-to-CDC.html]https://www.osusec.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/2022-10-05-Intro-to-CDC.html
Wish the Cyberforce team luck on November 4th-5th, and be sure to keep an eye out for an announcement about PRCCDC tryouts in mid-late November!</description></item><item><title>Meeting Notes 9/28</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-9-28/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-9-28/</guid><description>Howdy hackers! Thanks to everyone who showed up to the first meeting and we hope it was fun and informative!! Tonight we helped break in the new year for the club, and many people walked away from the meeting with new OSUSEC swag that they didn’t realize they were going to get!
Overall, we talked about the history and mission of OSUSEC, the various competitions we’re involved in, the events we hold, getting a CTF environment set up, some memes, and more!</description></item><item><title>Meeting Notes 2/23</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-2-23/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-2-23/</guid><description>Thank you to everyone who attended tonight’s meeting! We introduced several different CTF categories and what challenges usually look like within those categories. Then, we went over some of the challenges on the CTF Practice Range at https://ctf.osusec.org.
The slides for the meeting are available here (ONID Login Required): 2/23/2022 Slides
Later this week, we have this event coming up:
CTF League: This Friday, 6:00pm – 8:00pm (and every Friday during the term).</description></item><item><title>Meeting Notes 2/9</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-2-9/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-2-9/</guid><description>Thank you to everyone who attended tonight’s meeting! We chatted some more about reverse engineering, discussing the stack layout, function preambles and local variables on the stack. We introduced the rev02 challenge on the CTF Practice Range at https://ctf.osusec.org.
The slides for the meeting are available here (ONID Login Required): 2/9/2022 Slides
We have an interesting event coming up later this week:
CTF League: This Friday, 6:00pm – 8:00pm (and every Friday during the term).</description></item><item><title>Meeting Notes 3/2</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-3-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-3-2/</guid><description>Thank you to everyone who attended tonight’s meeting! We talked about what Wargames are, what their value is, and what some good starter wargames are to play.
The slides for the meeting are available here (ONID Login Required): 3/2/2022 Slides
Later this week, we have this event coming up:
CTF League: This Friday, 6:00pm – 8:00pm (and every Friday during the term). Elastic will be hosting a mini-CTF for us on Friday, it will be an awesome chance to learn about Elastic and win some prizes!</description></item><item><title>Meeting Notes 2/2</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-2-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-2-2/</guid><description>Thank you to everyone who attended tonight’s meeting! We chatted about reverse engineering and binary exploitation (pwn) tools and how to use them, and I demonstrated how to solve the rev01 challenge on the CTF Practice Range at https://ctf.osusec.org.
The slides for the meeting are available here (ONID Login Required): 2/2/2022 Slides
There are some interesting upcoming events which all club members are welcome at:
CTF League: This Friday, 6:00pm – 8:00pm (and every Friday during the term), we will have an awesome, real-world challenge for you to solve.</description></item><item><title>Meeting Notes 1/26</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-1-26/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-1-26/</guid><description>Thank you to everyone who attended! This meeting covered an introduction to reverse engineering on x86 64-bit. We covered some key differences between x86 and x86-64, then we examined how typical control flows are compiled to assembly based on the C source code.
Here are the slides (requires ONID login): Google Slides for 1/26/2021
The binary and C code that we looked at during tonight’s talk are posted on GitHub.</description></item><item><title>Meeting Notes 1/19</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-1-19/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-1-19/</guid><description>Thank you to everyone who attended! This meeting covered a presentation called “CS271 for Pwning”, an introduction to assembly and shellcoding with a focus on the useful aspects to pwning / binary exploitation.
Here are the slides (requires ONID login): Google Slides for 1/19/2021
The next meeting this week is for CTF League on Friday 1/21/2021 @ 6:00pm – 8:00pm, virtually (on Discord).</description></item><item><title>Meeting Notes 1/12</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-1-12/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-1-12/</guid><description>Thank you to everyone who attended! This meeting covered the solutions to all NSA Codebreaker 2021 Tasks. I hope everyone enjoyed, questions can always be tossed into the #nsacc-21 channel.
Here are the slides (requires ONID login): Google Slides for 1/12/2021
The next meeting this week is for CTF League on Friday 1/14/2021 @ 6:00pm – 8:00pm, virtually (on Discord).</description></item><item><title>Meeting Notes 10/27</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-10-27/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-10-27/</guid><description>Thank you to everyone who attended! This meeting covered an introduction to NSA Codebreaker Challenge, including some common tools and strategies used to solve challenges 0-6.
Here are the slides (requires ONID login): Google Slides for 10/27/2021
The next couple meetings will be as follows:
CTF League on Friday 10/29/2021 @ 6:00pm – 8:00pm in KEC 1003. We will be having pizza outside the room first (likely outside or in the atrium – see the CTF League Discord), followed by breaking up into teams and playing this week’s OSINT challenge by Cameron!</description></item><item><title>Meeting Notes 10/6</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-10-6/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-10-6/</guid><description>Thank you to all the members that attended this meeting! We covered lockpicking basics, legality and ethics, before Ryan presented a live demonstration of picking a lock. Then, each table had a selection of locks of increasing difficulty and tools to try to pick them with.
Here are the slides (requires ONID login): Google Slides for 10/6/2021
Next week (week of 10/11) we have two meetings:
Talk by NetSPI about NetSPI U on Wednesday 10/13/2021 @ 6:00pm – 7:00pm.</description></item><item><title>Meeting Notes 10/1</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-10-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-10-1/</guid><description>Thank you to everyone for coming to our first meeting this year! We had well over our expected 70 people in attendance. We introduced OSUSEC, what we do, how our Discord server works, as well as some ethics. We introduced members to Capture The Flag, and we delved into the first CTF League challenge of the year, a web challenge!
Here are the slides (requires ONID login): Google Slides for 10/1/2021</description></item><item><title>2021-2022 OSUSEC Officers Decided</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/2021-2022-osusec-officers-decided/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/2021-2022-osusec-officers-decided/</guid><description>For the coming school year, we welcome in 8 officers, in the following positions:
President: Lyell Read Vice President: Zach Taylor Treasurer: Mike Carris Lab Manager: Cameron McCawley Community Manager: Christa Wright Recruitment: Brandon Ellis CTF League Coordinator: Allen Benjamin Graphic Designer: Sierra Freihoefer This year is the first year that the posts of Recruitment Officer, CTF League Coordinator, and Community Manager were officially up for grabs. All three were positions that were voted in during the past year by the current officers, to respond to needs for these roles.</description></item><item><title>Meeting Notes 10/3</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-10-3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-10-3/</guid><description>Thanks for the great turnout again tonight! We went over some tools you can use for the NSA Codebreaker challenge.
Here is a link to the slides (requires ONID sign-in): Google Slides
Next week’s CTF meeting is slightly changed, it will be at 7pm in KEC 1003 on Tuesday, 10/8.</description></item><item><title>Meeting Notes 9/26</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-9-26/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-9-26/</guid><description>Thanks everyone for coming out to our first meeting! We had over 50 people in attendance, and introduced the OSU Security Club, what we do, what we stand for, our plans for the year, and worked on a couple introductory CTF challenges.
Here is a link to the slides (requires ONID login): Google Slides
Next week we have two meetings:
The first CTF meeting is Tuesday, 10/1 @ 6:30pm in KEC 1005.</description></item><item><title>NSA Visit</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/nsa-visit/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/nsa-visit/</guid><description>Yesterday the National Security Agency came to meet with some members of the university and give a talk to the OSU Security Club. The visit was a great success and we had over 100 people in attendance for the talk.
The talk was focused around the NSA Codebreaker Challenge, which just started last weekend (Oregon State won last year, and is currently in 2nd place). There was also a long Q&amp;amp;A session following the talk, where club members were able to ask questions about the challenge, in addition to general curiosities about the National Security Agency.</description></item><item><title>Meeting Notes 5/9</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-5-9/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-5-9/</guid><description>Today we hosted Ryan Gurr and Alex Ryan from Fidelis Cybersecurity, who talked about their experiences and background in information security, and showed a cool demo of Fidelis’s platform.
If you have any questions for Ryan or Alex, please contact them, they said they’d love to answer any questions you may have, related to Fidelis or not. You can get their contact info here.</description></item><item><title>2019-2020 Officers</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/2019-2020-officers/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/2019-2020-officers/</guid><description>Here are the new officers for the 2019-2020 school year:
President: Zander Work Vice President: Hadi Rahal-Arabi Treasurer: David Park Multimedia Coordinator: Adam Stewart Lab Manager: Ryan Kennedy Recruitment/Public Relations: Alex Rash Thanks to everyone who participated!</description></item><item><title>Meeting Notes 4/18</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-4-18/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-4-18/</guid><description>Tonight I gave a tutorial on IDA Pro basics, and how to get started with this awesome tool. I also released some new binaries on the CTF site for you to practice IDA.
Remember, as a OSU Security Club member you have access to our lab systems, which has the full version of IDA Pro and the Hex-Rays Decompiler installed, so make sure to use those if you want to take advantage of the advanced functionality.</description></item><item><title>2019-2020 Officer Elections on April 25th</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/2019-2020-officer-elections-on-april-25th/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/2019-2020-officer-elections-on-april-25th/</guid><description>We will be holding officer elections for next school year during our regular meeting on Week 4 (April 25th). This is a great way to be more involved with the club, and represent us to the College of Engineering.
Here are the positions (link goes to position duties):
President Vice President Treasurer Multimedia Coordinator Lab Manager To run for a position, please do the following:
Fill out this form no later than April 23rd Send a slide (one slide) to security.</description></item><item><title>Meeting Notes - 3/7</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-3-7/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-3-7/</guid><description>Thanks to Kees Cook for an awesome look at kernel security! Kees talked about how the kernel exploit for CVE-2017-7038 was discovered, which allowed privilege escalation due to a heap overflow.
You can see his slides here, which also has information for building the POC images for the exploit.
This was our last meeting for Winter 2019, so I’ll see you all next term! Our first meeting will be on Week 2.</description></item><item><title>Meeting 2/28 - OSUSEC Lab</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-2-28-osusec-lab/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-2-28-osusec-lab/</guid><description>Tonight I talked about the new OSUSEC lab environment! A few systems are currently live, and more will be coming up through the end of the term, including the self-registration system. For information about the lab environment, please see the dedicated page for it.</description></item><item><title>Meeting 2/21</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-2-21/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-2-21/</guid><description>Tonight we hosted Karl Fosaaen from NetSPI, and he gave an awesome talk on pentesting in an Azure environment.
If you’re interested in learning more about this, check out the NetSPI blog or the Azure pentesting book he mentioned. Karl’s post on using Azure RunAs certificates is now live here.</description></item><item><title>Meeting 2/14</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-2-14/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-2-14/</guid><description>Tonight I went over some basic usage of GDB, IDA Pro, and pwntools for solving the first pwnables on our CTF site.
Link to the slides (requires ONID login). The slides have information on getting the tools installed, so if you are having issues with that, check the slides out.</description></item><item><title>Meeting 2/7</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-2-7/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-2-7/</guid><description>Today we continued discussing reverse engineering and introduced 64-bit assembly. There are more samples on the GitHub repo.
The only announcement for today is to RSVP for our upcoming event with NetSPI! They will be coming back on 2/21 to do a presentation on penetration testing, and answer any questions you may have. The RSVP is just so I can get a head count for pizza. RSVP here
There are new challenges up on CTFd, rev[1-3]-64.</description></item><item><title>Meeting 1/31</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-1-31/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-1-31/</guid><description>Today we talked about some basic reverse engineering, and compare/contrasting x86 assembly with C code.
There are some new challenges up on CTFd, rev[1-4]
Link to the slides (requires ONID login)</description></item><item><title>Meeting 1/24</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-1-24/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-1-24/</guid><description>Tonight we worked on buffer overflows, and some binaries on the new OSUSEC CTF platform.
Slides (requires ONID login)
Next week, we’re going to work on similar binaries, but comparing the assembly code with the C code.</description></item><item><title>Meeting 1/17</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-1-17/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-1-17/</guid><description>Tonight we talked about some CTF tools and did a walkthrough for “start” on pwnable.tw. You can read a detailed writeup for this binary on the OSUSEC GitHub.
Here’s a link to the slides (requires ONID login): Slides
For those of you who felt lost tonight, my apologies! I received some great feedback, and will have some easier binaries for next week, which will allow me to work on establishing a better baseline for everyone.</description></item><item><title>Meeting 1/10</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-1-10/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-1-10/</guid><description>Thanks for a great first meeting for Winter 2019!
Here is a link to the slides (requires ONID login): Slides
For those of you who were unable to make it, here’s a brief summary of what we went over. Mostly, it was just talking about what’s coming for the rest of the term:
Updates on the OSUSEC Lab It’s coming. Windows is almost ready and then I’ll be working on Linux.</description></item><item><title>Welcome to Winter 2019!</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/welcome-to-winter-2019/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/welcome-to-winter-2019/</guid><description>Happy New Years! Our first meeting will be this Thursday at 7pm in KEC1003, and we will be meeting at the same time/place the whole term.
Some things to look forward to for this term:
I’m working with NetSPI to have them come back with a more technical presentation and hopefully some labs, so that will be awesome. PRCCDC is in March, with qualifiers in Februrary, so we will be working on putting together a team for that.</description></item><item><title>Meeting 11/15</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-11-15/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-11-15/</guid><description>Thanks for a great last meeting for the Fall term!
I gave a talk on all of the low-level architecture and x86 assembly content needed to get started with binary pwning, here is a link to the slides. Hopefully, this is enough to get you all started!
Have a great winter break!</description></item><item><title>Meeting 11/01</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-11-01/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-11-01/</guid><description>Thanks to Karl Fosaaen from NetSPI for the awesome presentation on an introduction to penetration testing! Remember, if you want to learn about these things on your own, please make sure to do it on your own network and devices. I’ll update this post with a link to the slides when they become available.
I don’t have any announcements for this week, so I’ll see you all next week!</description></item><item><title>Meeting 10/25</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-10-25/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-10-25/</guid><description>Thanks to Emily for the great talk on SIEMs (Security Incident and Event Management)! Here is a link to the slides.
Announcements from tonight’s meeting:
Make sure to RSVP for the NetSPI event happening next week (during our normal meeting time)! Here is a link to the form. Oct. 25 is the last day to RSVP. Those of you on the team for Cyberforce Competition, make sure to send your badge forms to PNNL.</description></item><item><title>Meeting 10/11</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-10-11/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-10-11/</guid><description>Thanks Zach for the awesome presentation tonight on Network Security Monitoring! I’ll update this post with a link to the slides once they are available.
Announcements from tonight’s meeting:
Make sure you are on Discord/SLI. Links are on the homepage for those. We will be hosting NetSPI on November 1st. They will be bringing pizza, so please RSVP for this so we can get a head count and information on dietary restrictions.</description></item><item><title>Meeting 10/4</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-10-4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-10-4/</guid><description>Thanks to Akshith for a great presentation on Blockchain! For those of you who were unable to make it, here is a link to the slides: https://drive.google.com/file/d/1-PVTrV6JO6DFnFFz415_JvZ52J-DXJqw/view?usp=sharing
Announcements from today’s meeting:
If you are interested in working in the Information Security Office here at OSU, make sure to apply here: https://jobs.oregonstate.edu/postings/67398. If you have any questions, please contact Emily Longman. No meeting next week (10/11) Applications for Cyberforce Competition will close on October 10th, please fill that out if you are interested: https://goo.</description></item><item><title>Meeting 9/27</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-9-27/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-9-27/</guid><description>Thanks for the awesome turnout tonight! I’ll make a permanent reservation for that space, as it seems like we have a lot more members this year, which is fantastic!
Here is a link to the slides for tonight’s meeting: https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1FyKIu0n8VOtbkOpgnoEFbv3iV2xa7JGM1sUMZdFvLKg/edit?usp=sharing (NOTE: you need to sign in with your OSU account to view them)
Please make sure you register with the club via SLI (Link: https://apps.ideal-logic.com/osusli?key=F3T9-25VWY_5878-CZ4R_bc14da8b).
This weekend we (officers) will be revamping the resources page to provide some guidance for those who are brand new to security and those who have been 1337 pwners for years alike.</description></item></channel></rss>