<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>OSU Security Club</title><link>https://osusec.org/</link><description>Recent content on OSU Security Club</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 10:10:33 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://osusec.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>CTF Meetings</title><link>https://osusec.org/home/blurb/ctf-meetings/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/home/blurb/ctf-meetings/</guid><description>OSUSEC meets regularly to play, discuss, and learn Capture The Flag. When there’s not a global pandemic, we meet in KEC. When there is, we make do on Discord.</description></item><item><title>Guest Speakers</title><link>https://osusec.org/home/blurb/guest-speakers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/home/blurb/guest-speakers/</guid><description>We love hosting guest speakers from industry, higher ed, or the public sector to talk to our club. Please email us with the address below if you’d like to speak to our club members!</description></item><item><title>Competitions</title><link>https://osusec.org/home/blurb/competitions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/home/blurb/competitions/</guid><description>Our competition team (OSUSEC) competes in multiple Capture The Flag and Cyber Defense Competitions throughout the year.</description></item><item><title>Meeting 11/08/23</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-11-08-23/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 10:10:33 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-11-08-23/</guid><description>Ni Haowdy members!
Last night, we had our first lockpicking meeting of the school year! Zane led us through an introduction to lockpicking and the various locks we have. Lockpicking is a great outlet for puzzle-solving as well as a practical tool if you are ever locked out of our apartment :)
We will continue to have lockpicking meetings throughout the year, so keep an eye out for the next one!</description></item><item><title>Cyberforce 2023</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/cyberforce-2023/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2023 10:10:16 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/cyberforce-2023/</guid><description>Last weekend, OSUSEC&amp;rsquo;s cyberdefense team flew out to Chicago to compete in the Department of Energy&amp;rsquo;s Cyberforce Competition! For 4 out of 6 members of the team, this was their very first time in a cyberdefense competition, and they absolutely rocked it! The team trained on Industrial Control Systems, system administration, and incident response in preparation, and came away with 15th out of 95 teams!
Thank you for everyone who helped put on Cyberforce.</description></item><item><title>Meeting 11/01/23</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-11-01-23/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 10:10:30 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-11-01-23/</guid><description>Happy start of winter, members!
Last night, we held a working party for the NSA Codebreaker Challenge! Lucas introduced each of the tasks and discussed the rewards for high-achievers and solvers. Lucas also showcased some of the challenge coins available from other competitions that we have participated and placed in. The Challenge is a great opportunity for beginners and skilled hackers alike; the tasks steadily increase in difficulty and are a fantastic way to learn something new!</description></item><item><title>WWT Red Team CyberRange</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/wwt-red-team/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2023 10:10:45 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/wwt-red-team/</guid><description>Last Thursday, we entered two teams into WWT&amp;rsquo;s red team CyberRange! The competition tasked us with breaking into the infrastructure of a fake ransomware group. Aside from an engaging and topical theme, it gave us a chance to put our offensive skills to the test as we exploited Windows machines, achieved remote code execution via PHP, pivoted around their environment, and lost our sanity to DNS.
Our teams were able to bring home 2nd and 4th place out of 18 teams total, with several other universities competing.</description></item><item><title>Armis Workshop</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/armis-workshop/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 09:54:35 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/armis-workshop/</guid><description>Last Friday night, we were very fortunate to host Terry Boedeker of Armis to discuss IoT security in preparation for Cyberforce next weekend!
He talked about the importance of cyber-physical security and guided us through a hands-on lab with Armis&amp;rsquo; flagship SIEM, tracing exploit attempts and hidden devices on the demo network. It was super valuable and everyone really enjoyed getting to hear this unique industry perspective! We had 28 students come out and participate, and great informal conversations afterward!</description></item><item><title>Meeting 10/25/23</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-10-25-23/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2023 20:11:05 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-10-25-23/</guid><description>Good Thursday, members!
Last night we got to hear from Isabel Boona from Battelle! She presented on her work in reverse-engineering microchips, and how her previous work in materials science helped her transition into this unique line of work! This work is especially important when verifying that systems have been built without unintentional bugs and malicious backdoors.
Battelle is one of the largest non-profits dedicated to research in the United States, and manages many of the National Laboratories on behalf of the Department of Energy, as well as doing Top Secret contract work with the federal government.</description></item><item><title>Meeting 10/18/23</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-10-18-23/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 12:04:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-10-18-23/</guid><description>Ni Haowdy!
Last night, we hosted Dr. Kelsey Fulton of the Colorado School of Mines. They talked about their research into the why and the how that software developers introduce security vulnerabilities into their code, and some potential solutions for it. We had some great conversations about the attitudes in software development spaces and how we might be able to change that for the future. Please reach out to Dr. Fulton if you are interested in working with them on further research!</description></item><item><title>Meeting 10/11/23</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-10-11-23/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2023 13:41:15 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-10-11-23/</guid><description>Howdy hackers!
Last night, we had the fantastic Jonathan Keller give a talk about how he used his pwn skills in order to get a world record in a Tool Assisted Speedrun of Super Metroid! Thank you everyone who showed up :) He discussed the game&amp;rsquo;s internal mechanics, how the exploit works, and his experience developing the real-world exploit as a cybersecurity student and as someone who enjoys retro games.</description></item><item><title>Meeting 10/04/23</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-10-04-23/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 14:44:22 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-10-04-23/</guid><description>Howdy hackers!
Thanks for showing up last night, and staying flexible with us! I know we weren&amp;rsquo;t able to host the meeting we wanted at the last minute, but hopefully you got to enjoy some memes, learn about the club, and possibly pick a lock for the first time! We hope to see you again in more meetings throughout the term. Please feel free to reach out to any officer if you have questions or need help!</description></item><item><title>WWT Blue Team CyberRange</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/wwt-blue-team/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 17:24:37 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/wwt-blue-team/</guid><description>Last Thursday, OSUSEC assembled a team of 4 students to compete in WWT&amp;rsquo;s fantastic blue team CyberRange! We had a ton of fun and are very proud to announce that we placed 3rd, going up against a mixture of teams including those from federal agencies &amp;amp; Fortune 500 companies! We played from 3pm to 3am the next morning, all in one shot. The crash afterwards was not pleasant but it was still worth it &amp;ndash; incident response and cyber competitions take on a wilder and much more creative tone when it&amp;rsquo;s an odd hour in the morning.</description></item><item><title>NCCDC 2023</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/nccdc-2023/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2023 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/nccdc-2023/</guid><description>The last weekend of April, OSUSEC’s Cyber Defense team competed in NCCDC, the National Collegiate Cyber Defense Competition. The competition required us to secure and administer a handful of networks full of virtual machines hosting common business services, as well as continuously respond to IT request tickets and deliver professional reports to supervisors. Students are tested not only on their cybersecurity skills, but also on their time management and interpersonal skills.</description></item><item><title>2023-2024 OSUSEC Officers Selected</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/2023-2024-osusec-officers-selected/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/2023-2024-osusec-officers-selected/</guid><description>This year’s elections were intense; every candidate was subjected to memes, music, and whiteboard art that led to a lot of laughs and a lot of great people elected. Without further adieu, here are your officers for the 2023-2024 academic year:
President: Casey Colley Vice President: Otso Barron Treasurer: Abigail Whittle Lab Manager: Lucas Ball CTF League Coordinator: Zane Othman-Gomez Recruitment and Community Outreach Manager: Julie Weber
Thank you to all who came (or attended on Discord) and took part in democracy!</description></item><item><title>PRCCDC 2023</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/prccdc-2023/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2023 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/prccdc-2023/</guid><description>This past weekend, OSUSEC’s Cyber Defense team competed in PRCCDC, our regional Collegiate Cyber Defense Competition. The competition required us to secure and administer a handful of networks full of virtual machines hosting common business services, as well as continuously respond to IT request tickets and deliver professional reports to supervisors. Students are tested not only on their cybersecurity skills, but also on their time management and interpersonal skills. OSUSEC walked away with 1st place, and will be attending NCCDC (Nationals) at the end of April!</description></item><item><title>Meeting Notes 11/09</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-11-09/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-11-09/</guid><description>Howdy hackers! Last night, I covered cybersecurity in software development. I talked about how you can incorporate security into each stage of the Software Development Lifecycle, some examples of how that has gone wrong in real life software projects, and the different mitigations that have come about in an effort to control memory corruption attacks (an example of improper input handling).
The slides for the meeting are available here (ONID required): https://docs.</description></item><item><title>Cyberforce Competition 2022</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/cyberforce-competition-2022/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/cyberforce-competition-2022/</guid><description>This past weekend, OSUSEC’s Cyberdefense Competition team flew out to Chicago, IL to compete in the Department of Energy’s Cyberforce Competition! We were tasked with securing and administering a network of 6 virtual machines, then defending it against a team of hackers. Cyberforce also tests students’ abilities to budget their time and respond to miscellaneous requests from managers relating to the NIST framework for cybersecurity. We brought home 10th place out of 169 teams, and placed 1st place for team style 😎</description></item><item><title>Meeting Notes 11/02</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-11-02/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-11-02/</guid><description>Howdy hackers! Welcome to the second half of Fall term! Tonight we hosted NetSPI: Senior Director Karl Fosaaen and Security Consultant (and former club member) Michael Jereza. They walked us through penetration testing as a career, what work is like at NetSPI, their NetSPI University program, and some entertaining stories from their pentesting work! We hope you had fun and walked away with an enthusiasm for pentesting. If you enjoyed this, definitely think about getting involved with our CPTC team!</description></item><item><title>Meeting Notes 10/19</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-10-19/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-10-19/</guid><description>Howdy hackers! Hope your week 4 is going well. Tonight Cameron introduced Reversed Engineering (“Rev”) challenges and how to pwn them. Rev and pwn challenges are a staple of CTF competitions, and we covered a few of the most critical tools in your arsenal for approaching them. We also walked you through an introductory pwn challenge called rev01 that is hosted on our CTF Practice Range. We hope you were able to walk away with some new skills.</description></item><item><title>Meeting Notes 10/12</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-10-12/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-10-12/</guid><description>Howdy hackers! Thanks to everyone who showed up tonight! Tonight we introduced the NSA Codebreaker Challenge, and held a work party. Hopefully you were able to make some progress on Tasks in a focused environment and get free dinner! We covered previous year’s Codebreaker themes, the NSA’s mission and how that inspires the Challenge, and introduced the different tools that the NSA recommends to approach the Challenge with.
The slides for the meeting are available here (ONID required): https://docs.</description></item><item><title>BSidesPDX 2022</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/bsidespdx-2022/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/bsidespdx-2022/</guid><description>Howdy Hackers! This Friday, a group of OSUSEC members took a day trip up to Portland to attend BSidesPDX 2022 and compete in their CTF. We had an absolute blast, winning first place in the CTF, attending many interesting talks, and making some new friends! We became known as the team competing in the closet, as the CTF team set up fort in a nearby maintenance closet instead of the official CTF room.</description></item><item><title>Meeting Notes 10/05</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-10-05/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-10-05/</guid><description>Howdy hackers! Thanks to everyone who showed up, and we hope it was enjoyable and informative! Tonight we introduced Cyber Defense Competitions. We covered some of the skills and areas you would learn by playing in a CDC, what makes them fun, and the career advantages of getting involved in them!
The slides for the meeting are available here: [https://www.osusec.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/2022-10-05-Intro-to-CDC.html]https://www.osusec.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/2022-10-05-Intro-to-CDC.html
Wish the Cyberforce team luck on November 4th-5th, and be sure to keep an eye out for an announcement about PRCCDC tryouts in mid-late November!</description></item><item><title>Meeting Notes 9/28</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-9-28/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-9-28/</guid><description>Howdy hackers! Thanks to everyone who showed up to the first meeting and we hope it was fun and informative!! Tonight we helped break in the new year for the club, and many people walked away from the meeting with new OSUSEC swag that they didn’t realize they were going to get!
Overall, we talked about the history and mission of OSUSEC, the various competitions we’re involved in, the events we hold, getting a CTF environment set up, some memes, and more!</description></item><item><title>2022-2023 OSUSEC Officers Decided</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/2022-2023-osusec-officers-decided/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/2022-2023-osusec-officers-decided/</guid><description>The votes are in! After an entertaining election with some contested positions and contestants running from the floor, the officers for the next academic year, 2022-2023.
President: Cameron McCawley Vice President: Casey Colley Treasurer: Mike Carris Lab Manager: Lucas Ball CTF League Coordinator: Allen Benjamin Recruitment Officer: Brandon Ellis (Interim) Community Manager: Gabriel Kulp
Thanks to everyone who participated!</description></item><item><title>Meeting Notes 2/23</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-2-23/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-2-23/</guid><description>Thank you to everyone who attended tonight’s meeting! We introduced several different CTF categories and what challenges usually look like within those categories. Then, we went over some of the challenges on the CTF Practice Range at https://ctf.osusec.org.
The slides for the meeting are available here (ONID Login Required): 2/23/2022 Slides
Later this week, we have this event coming up:
CTF League: This Friday, 6:00pm – 8:00pm (and every Friday during the term).</description></item><item><title>Meeting Notes 2/9</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-2-9/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-2-9/</guid><description>Thank you to everyone who attended tonight’s meeting! We chatted some more about reverse engineering, discussing the stack layout, function preambles and local variables on the stack. We introduced the rev02 challenge on the CTF Practice Range at https://ctf.osusec.org.
The slides for the meeting are available here (ONID Login Required): 2/9/2022 Slides
We have an interesting event coming up later this week:
CTF League: This Friday, 6:00pm – 8:00pm (and every Friday during the term).</description></item><item><title>Meeting Notes 3/2</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-3-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-3-2/</guid><description>Thank you to everyone who attended tonight’s meeting! We talked about what Wargames are, what their value is, and what some good starter wargames are to play.
The slides for the meeting are available here (ONID Login Required): 3/2/2022 Slides
Later this week, we have this event coming up:
CTF League: This Friday, 6:00pm – 8:00pm (and every Friday during the term). Elastic will be hosting a mini-CTF for us on Friday, it will be an awesome chance to learn about Elastic and win some prizes!</description></item><item><title>Meeting Notes 2/2</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-2-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-2-2/</guid><description>Thank you to everyone who attended tonight’s meeting! We chatted about reverse engineering and binary exploitation (pwn) tools and how to use them, and I demonstrated how to solve the rev01 challenge on the CTF Practice Range at https://ctf.osusec.org.
The slides for the meeting are available here (ONID Login Required): 2/2/2022 Slides
There are some interesting upcoming events which all club members are welcome at:
CTF League: This Friday, 6:00pm – 8:00pm (and every Friday during the term), we will have an awesome, real-world challenge for you to solve.</description></item><item><title>Meeting Notes 1/26</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-1-26/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-1-26/</guid><description>Thank you to everyone who attended! This meeting covered an introduction to reverse engineering on x86 64-bit. We covered some key differences between x86 and x86-64, then we examined how typical control flows are compiled to assembly based on the C source code.
Here are the slides (requires ONID login): Google Slides for 1/26/2021
The binary and C code that we looked at during tonight’s talk are posted on GitHub.</description></item><item><title>Meeting Notes 1/19</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-1-19/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-1-19/</guid><description>Thank you to everyone who attended! This meeting covered a presentation called “CS271 for Pwning”, an introduction to assembly and shellcoding with a focus on the useful aspects to pwning / binary exploitation.
Here are the slides (requires ONID login): Google Slides for 1/19/2021
The next meeting this week is for CTF League on Friday 1/21/2021 @ 6:00pm – 8:00pm, virtually (on Discord).</description></item><item><title>Meeting Notes 1/12</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-1-12/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-1-12/</guid><description>Thank you to everyone who attended! This meeting covered the solutions to all NSA Codebreaker 2021 Tasks. I hope everyone enjoyed, questions can always be tossed into the #nsacc-21 channel.
Here are the slides (requires ONID login): Google Slides for 1/12/2021
The next meeting this week is for CTF League on Friday 1/14/2021 @ 6:00pm – 8:00pm, virtually (on Discord).</description></item><item><title>NSA Codebreaker Challenge 2021</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/nsa-codebreaker-challenge-2021/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/nsa-codebreaker-challenge-2021/</guid><description>On January 4th, 2021, OSUSEC finished 3rd place with 133,337 points at the NSA Codebreaker Challenge. 189 OSU students and OSUSEC members solved at least one of the 11 tasks, and 5 OSU students and OSUSEC members solved all 11.
Some more statistics about the competition are below:
Confirmed Public Participants: 5,465 Schools Registered: 631 Task Completions: Task 0: 3,335 Task 1: 2,352 Task 2: 1,385 Task 3: 1,098 Task 4: 778 Task 5: 688 Task 6: 418 Task 7: 196 Task 8: 56 Task 9: 55 Task 10: 42 PCAP Downloads: 3,650 This was a great effort from our team over the course of several months.</description></item><item><title>DOE Cyberforce Competition 2021</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/doe-cyberforce-competition-2021/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Nov 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/doe-cyberforce-competition-2021/</guid><description>On Nov. 13, 2021, the OSUSEC Cyber Defense Competition (CDC) Team placed 1st place regionally and 7th nationwide in the Department of Energy’s annual Cyberforce Competition (https://cyberforcecompetition.com/) out of the 135 teams registered for the competition.
The team roster was:
Casey Colley (Captain) Mike Carris Robert Detjens Brandon Ellis Huy Nguyen Lyell Read The final scoreboard was as follows, if a link to an official final scoreboard is made available, I will link it here.</description></item><item><title>Meeting Notes 10/27</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-10-27/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-10-27/</guid><description>Thank you to everyone who attended! This meeting covered an introduction to NSA Codebreaker Challenge, including some common tools and strategies used to solve challenges 0-6.
Here are the slides (requires ONID login): Google Slides for 10/27/2021
The next couple meetings will be as follows:
CTF League on Friday 10/29/2021 @ 6:00pm – 8:00pm in KEC 1003. We will be having pizza outside the room first (likely outside or in the atrium – see the CTF League Discord), followed by breaking up into teams and playing this week’s OSINT challenge by Cameron!</description></item><item><title>Meeting Notes 10/6</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-10-6/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-10-6/</guid><description>Thank you to all the members that attended this meeting! We covered lockpicking basics, legality and ethics, before Ryan presented a live demonstration of picking a lock. Then, each table had a selection of locks of increasing difficulty and tools to try to pick them with.
Here are the slides (requires ONID login): Google Slides for 10/6/2021
Next week (week of 10/11) we have two meetings:
Talk by NetSPI about NetSPI U on Wednesday 10/13/2021 @ 6:00pm – 7:00pm.</description></item><item><title>Meeting Notes 10/1</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-10-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-10-1/</guid><description>Thank you to everyone for coming to our first meeting this year! We had well over our expected 70 people in attendance. We introduced OSUSEC, what we do, how our Discord server works, as well as some ethics. We introduced members to Capture The Flag, and we delved into the first CTF League challenge of the year, a web challenge!
Here are the slides (requires ONID login): Google Slides for 10/1/2021</description></item><item><title>2021-2022 OSUSEC Officers Decided</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/2021-2022-osusec-officers-decided/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/2021-2022-osusec-officers-decided/</guid><description>For the coming school year, we welcome in 8 officers, in the following positions:
President: Lyell Read Vice President: Zach Taylor Treasurer: Mike Carris Lab Manager: Cameron McCawley Community Manager: Christa Wright Recruitment: Brandon Ellis CTF League Coordinator: Allen Benjamin Graphic Designer: Sierra Freihoefer This year is the first year that the posts of Recruitment Officer, CTF League Coordinator, and Community Manager were officially up for grabs. All three were positions that were voted in during the past year by the current officers, to respond to needs for these roles.</description></item><item><title>0x41414141 CTF - 0x414141</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/0x41414141-ctf-0x414141/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/0x41414141-ctf-0x414141/</guid><description>Prompt I think offshift promised to opensource some of their code
author: notforsale
Solution First off, we navigate to the offshift-dev github account, linked from the offshift site. Unfortunately, nothing there. Searching google for “offshift github” brings us to a different github with a single suspicious repository. This has two commits, one where files are uploaded, and one in which the _pycache_ folder is deleted. That folder sounds interesting, so we clone the repository, and checkout the commit where the files were added:</description></item><item><title>Crowdstrike Adversary Quest - Much Sad</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/crowdstrike-adversary-quest-much-sad/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/crowdstrike-adversary-quest-much-sad/</guid><description>Prompt We have received some information that CATAPULT SPIDER has encrypted a client’s cat pictures and successfully extorted them for a ransom of 1337 Dogecoin. The client has provided the ransom note, is there any way for you to gather more information about the adversary’s online presence?
NOTE: Flags will be easily identifiable by following the format CS{some_secret_flag_text}. They must be submitted in full, including the CS{ and } parts.</description></item><item><title>BSidesPDX - Down the Rabbit Hole</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/bsidespdx-down-the-rabbit-hole/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/bsidespdx-down-the-rabbit-hole/</guid><description>Prompt Category: Over The Air
297 Points
5 Solves
During one of the commercial breaks of my favorite state sponsored educational video, there was some interference once again. There was a woman wearing some sort of face mask and there were strange tones. The tones were familiar and rang a bell, but I couldn’t quite put my finger on them. I don’t know what these things mean, but maybe you can figure it out.</description></item><item><title>BSidesPDX - Please Stand By</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/bsidespdx-please-stand-by/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/bsidespdx-please-stand-by/</guid><description>Prompt Category: Over The Air
263 Points
14 Solves
Sometimes I like to tune into the TV when no shows are on so I can watch the test pattern. I like to believe that there’s a secret message hidden in the transmission.
twitch.tv/over_the_air
Author(s): 0xdade &amp;amp; fdcarl
Solution This challenge is about the “Please Stand By” screen, presumably. Let’s start by looking there. This screen is displayed during the first 2:09 of the twitch stream(recording)</description></item><item><title>BSidesPDX - Xclusive Numborz</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/bsidespdx-xclusive-numborz/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/bsidespdx-xclusive-numborz/</guid><description>Prompt Category: Over The Air
290 Points
8 Solves
I was watching my regularly scheduled state sponsored programming when I got some strange interference. It sounded like a little girl was talking to me but I couldn’t understand what she was saying. Can you figure it out? There’s no space for mistakes, and no room for questions.
twitch.tv/over_the_air
Author(s): 0xdade &amp;amp; fdcarl
Solution The first challenge was easy, but this one is a little trickier.</description></item><item><title>EkoPartyCTF - Docs</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/ekopartyctf-docs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/ekopartyctf-docs/</guid><description>EkoParty CTF 2020 Git 2
Prompt Exact prompt has been forgotten. Linked to this GitHub repo
Solution As I mentioned in the writeup for leak, I was in a very githubby mindset when I started this challenge. For that reason, I solved this challenge first.
A quick inspection of the repo shows that it features an accidentally committed SSH private key and matching public key. I copied the text of these out of the commit log, and into chall and chall.</description></item><item><title>EkoPartyCTF - Env</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/ekopartyctf-env/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/ekopartyctf-env/</guid><description>EkoParty CTF 2020 Git 3
Prompt Not too sure of the original prompt, however I did not need it.
Solution After the second part of the git challenge saga, we have gotten a new repository with some new github actions. We know, before analyzing these however, that:
Issues filed to the ekolabs repo will be ‘moved’ to the ekoparty-internal repo. We control content in the submitted issues, and this is copied to the new issues in ekoparty-internal repo.</description></item><item><title>EkoPartyCTF - Leak</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/ekopartyctf-leak/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/ekopartyctf-leak/</guid><description>EkoParty CTF 2020 Git 1
Prompt Exact prompt has been forgotten. Linked to this GitHub repo
Solution This solution was quite obscure, as I approached this challenge in a github mindset, not a ctf::misc one. In light of this, I solved the second challenge first 😛
When I got on to solving this one, it took me several runs through the full commit history of the repo before seeing this:</description></item><item><title>Fword CTF - Identity Fraud</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/fword-ctf-identity-fraud/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/fword-ctf-identity-fraud/</guid><description>Points: 419 Solves: 86 Category: OSINT
Prompt Someone stole our logo and created a team named “Eword”. In order to find him, I created a fake twitter account (@1337bloggs) to join Eword team. Fortunately, they replied to the fake account and gave me a task to solve. So, if I solve it, they will accept me as a team member. … Can you help me in solving the task?
Flag Format: Eword{}</description></item><item><title>NahamConCTF - Finsta</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/nahamconctf-finsta/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/nahamconctf-finsta/</guid><description>50 points
Prompt This time we have a username. Can you track down NahamConTron?
Solution I used the namechk tools from the OSINT Framework Site. Specifically, I used OSINT Framework &amp;gt; Username &amp;gt; Username Search Engines &amp;gt; Namechk, similarly to in AUCTF.
namechk tells me that there are claimed usernames for the name NahamConTron for many sites, including Instagram.
Checking out the Instagram account, we get the flag.
flag{i_feel_like_that_was_too_easy} ~ Lyell</description></item><item><title>NahamConcTF - Microosoft</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/nahamconctf-microosoft/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/nahamconctf-microosoft/</guid><description>100 points
Prompt We have to use Microsoft Word at the office!? Oof…
Download the file below.
File
Solution Opening the file does not do much, but it would not be that easy.
Using file we can find out that this is an OOXML document:
$ file microsooft.docx microsooft.docx: Microsoft OOXML Based on this, and some quick reading, we can see that this format can contain files. To view these files, I first tried this chrome extension, before settling on getting a trial licensed version of OxygenXML.</description></item><item><title>NahamConCTF - Time Keeper</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/nahamconctf-time-keeper/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/nahamconctf-time-keeper/</guid><description>50 points
Prompt There is some interesting stuff on this website. Or at least, I thought there was…
Connect here: https://apporima.com/
Note, this flag is not in the usual format.
Solution After scoping out that site, the title and description heavily hint towards use of the Wayback Machine. Over there we head, then.
First, I noted that there were only two captures, so I figured it would be worth it to compare them.</description></item><item><title>NahamConCTF - Tron</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/nahamconctf-tron/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/nahamconctf-tron/</guid><description>75 points
Prompt NahamConTron is up to more shenanigans. Find his server.
Solution I used the namechk tools from the OSINT Framework Site. Specifically, I used OSINT Framework &amp;gt; Username &amp;gt; Username Search Engines &amp;gt; Namechk, similarly to in AUCTF.
namechk tells me that there are claimed usernames for the name NahamConTron for many sites:
Now that we have exhausted Instagram, I opened up all the other sites with claimed usernames for NahamConTron and systematically eliminated them.</description></item><item><title>Thank You</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/thank-you/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/thank-you/</guid><description>Being your club president for the last 3 years has been an incredible experience. Back in Fall 2017 when I first came to OSU, the club had maybe 20-30 members and wasn’t involved in CTF or CDC at all. Now, we’ve reached nearly 300 members, play CTF nearly every weekend, and have many 1st place and top 3 finishes in CDC, not to mention our incredible 1st and 3rd place finishes in the NSA Codebreaker Challenge.</description></item><item><title>HouseplantCTF - Catography Writeup</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/houseplantctf-catography-writeup/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/houseplantctf-catography-writeup/</guid><description>Prompt Jubie’s released her own collection of cat pictures. Go check it out!
http://challs.houseplant.riceteacatpanda.wtf:30002
Note: The Unsplash author credit is not a part of the challenge, it’s only there to conform with the Unsplash image license.
Dev: jammy
Solution Browsing the site, we can see that it is a collection of cat images… A lot of them. From inspecting the sources, we can see that these images are pulled from an API at http://challs.</description></item><item><title>HouseplantCTF Satan's Jigsaw Writeup</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/houseplantctf-satans-jigsaw-writeup/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/houseplantctf-satans-jigsaw-writeup/</guid><description>Prompt Oh no! I dropped my pixels on the floor and they’re all muddled up! It’s going to take me years to sort all 90,000 of these again 🙁
Dev: Tom
Hint! long_to_bytes
File: chall.7z
Solution This provided archive contains 90,000 JPEG’s. I extracted all of them to ./images (relative to this README’s PWD). Each of these images has a size of 1 pixel.
Then, comes the fun part. Before reading the hint, I tried just forming the image from the pixels in the order that they appeared in the folder, but this revealed a ‘static’ image.</description></item><item><title>IJCTF - Vault Writeup</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/ijctf-vault-writeup/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/ijctf-vault-writeup/</guid><description>Prompt We locked our secret box, You can directly ping the bot (@Vault #8895 ) using “start” to get the secret but we don’t know the door code we used random() also we used sleep(10).
shift register…
Author : Harsh and warlock_rootx
Hint: if pin in user_input(): #Good Stuff…
Solution This problem (and especially the hint) make clear what we have to do. We need to provide the discord bot with as many possible passcodes as we can for the suggested charset and length as possible… now, discord makes this hard, as messages are limited to 2000 characters.</description></item><item><title>PRCCDC 2020 Results</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/prccdc-2020-results/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/prccdc-2020-results/</guid><description>Due to the current COVID-19 pandemic, the in-person Pacific Rim Collegiate Cyber Defense Competition (PRCCDC) was unfortunately cancelled. However, PRCCDC, working in combination with NCCDC, allowed all of the Pacific Rim teams to compete in the National Wildcard Event, which was held online on April 11th, 2020.
I am pleased to announce that OSUSEC placed 2nd in the PRCCDC division (out of 12 teams), and 9th overall (out of 26 teams)!</description></item><item><title>ByteBanditsCTF - string.equals(integer) Writeup</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/bytebanditsctf-string-equals-integer-writeup/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/bytebanditsctf-string-equals-integer-writeup/</guid><description>Prompt Someone gave me two functions to convert strings into integers. I converted some strings to the integers and noted them down. Can you help me converting the concatenation of those strings in the order mentioned in the file hashes.txt into integers?
The answer for this is the multiplication of output of both the functions for the concatenated string. (Wrap the number around flag{})
File: hash.zip
Solution The problem, after a couple read-throughs and looking at the files provided, makes clear that to generate hashes.</description></item><item><title>AUCTF - ALIedAS About Some Thing</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/auctf-aliedas-about-some-thing/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/auctf-aliedas-about-some-thing/</guid><description>903 points
Prompt See what you can find.
AUCTFShh
Author: c
Solution AUCTFShh looks like a username. To find where that username is in use, we can either check manually (as I started out doing), or use some tools from the OSINT Framework Site. Specifically, I used OSINT Framework &amp;gt; Username &amp;gt; Username Search Engines &amp;gt; Namechk.
I opened each of the greyed out sites in a tab, and looked through each for anything suspicious.</description></item><item><title>AUCTF - Good Old Days</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/auctf-good-old-days/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/auctf-good-old-days/</guid><description>877 points
Prompt This site used to look a lot cooler.
Author: c
Solution Wayback Machine, here I come! This is the most useful view of the captures for the site ctf.auburn.edu: https://web.archive.org/web/sitemap/https://ctf.auburn.edu/. It shows that, among other subdirectories (and trust me, I visited each a couple times), the /users and /users/50 pages have both been captured.
https://web.archive.org/web/20200213064621/https://ctf.auburn.edu/users has a user called auctf{Th053_w3rE_Th3_guD_0l3_d4y5} – why it has to be at the end of that page, I don’t know (I checked the top half a couple times during my research).</description></item><item><title>AUCTF - OSINT You All Over the Place</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/auctf-osint-you-all-over-the-place/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/auctf-osint-you-all-over-the-place/</guid><description>A post-competition writeup; 983 points
Prompt I do not have access to the prompt, but the URL is devs-r-us.xyz
Solution After solving the first three challenges, I looked into this one. I investigated the website provided thouroughly, and found out the following:
Images mcofee.png and mcafee.png are different, their difference contains some data and a discord link (applicable to Oryx, the last OSINT challenge). Loretta Mcintosh (with twitter handle @BackUpOrMcintoshYouOut) and Jorge Greenwood (@JorgeGreenwoodCodes), and two sites listed in Jorge Greenwood’s Bio, all of which are dead ends on Wayback Machine and at the time of writing (facepalm.</description></item><item><title>AUCTF - Who Made Me</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/auctf-who-made-me/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/auctf-who-made-me/</guid><description>950 points
Prompt One of the developers of this CTF worked really hard on this challenge.
note: the answer is not the author’s name
Author: c
Solution: Now for a much more real-world OSINT challenge. First, I started by doing a bit of recon. I ascertained that:
AU in AUCTF is for Auburn University (homeapge) AUCTF is run by members of the AUEHC (Auburn University Ethical Hacking Club). AUEHC is comprised of members: President – Jordan Sosnowski: jjs@auburn.</description></item><item><title>MidnightsunCTF Snake++</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/midnightsunctf-snake/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/midnightsunctf-snake/</guid><description>Prompt 141 points, 38 solves
Snake Oil Co. has invented a special programming language to play their new and improved version of Snake. Beat the game to get the flag. settings Service: nc snakeplusplus-01.play.midnightsunctf.se 55555
Solution When I first connected to the remote server, I was presented with a menu, detailing 3 options: Play in player mode, play in computer mode, or exit. The rules detail that a score of 42 will grant you a flag, so I first tried in player mode (where I direct the snake).</description></item><item><title>NahamConCTF - Fake File</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/nahamconctf-fake-file/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/nahamconctf-fake-file/</guid><description>100 points
Prompt Wait… where is the flag?
Connect here: nc jh2i.com 50026
Solution Let’s nc to that server and see what’s up:
$ nc jh2i.com 50026 bash: cannot set terminal process group (1): Inappropriate ioctl for device bash: no job control in this shell user@host:/home/user$ ls -lah ls -lah total 12K dr-xr-xr-x 1 nobody nogroup 4.0K Jun 12 17:10 . drwxr-xr-x 1 user user 4.0K Jun 4 18:54 .. -rw-r--r-- 1 user user 52 Jun 12 17:10 .</description></item><item><title>FireshellCTF Against the Perfect discord Inquisitor 1 and 2</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/fireshellctf-against-the-perfect-discord-inquisitor-1-and-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/fireshellctf-against-the-perfect-discord-inquisitor-1-and-2/</guid><description>Prompt 1 You’re on a journey and come to the Tavern of a Kingdom Enemy, you need to get information of a secret organization for the next quest. Be careful about the Inquisitor! He can ban you from this world.
TL;DR find the flag
Kingdom Chall
HINT: Title/Chall name
Prompt 2 There is a mage in the tavern that reveals secrets from the place. He is friendly, so he can help you!</description></item><item><title>TAMUCTF - ALCAPONE</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/tamuctf-alcapone/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/tamuctf-alcapone/</guid><description>Prompt Eliot Ness is the lead on taking down Al Capone. He has gained access to Capone’s personal computer but being the good detective he is, he got the disk image of the computer rather than look through the actual computer. Can you help Ness out and find any information to take down the mob boss?
(hint: Al Capone knew his computer was going to be taken soon, so he deleted all important data to ensure no one could see it.</description></item><item><title>TAMUCTF - GEOGRAPHY</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/tamuctf-geography/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/tamuctf-geography/</guid><description>Prompt My friend told me that she found something cool on the Internet, but all she sent me was 11000010100011000111111111101110 and 11000001100101000011101111011111.
She’s always been a bit cryptic. She told me to “surround with gigem{} that which can be seen from a bird’s eye view”… what?
Solution Ok. We know that we need to somehow interpret those binary strings as coordinate(s) to get a location that we can look at from “bird’s eye view” (presumably on Google Maps).</description></item><item><title>TAMUCTF - RUSSIAN_NESTING_DOLLS</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/tamuctf-russian_nesting_dolls/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/tamuctf-russian_nesting_dolls/</guid><description>Prompt Our monitoring systems noticed some funny-looking DNS traffic on one of our computers. We have the network logs from around the time of the incident. Want to take a look?
Files: netlogs.pcap
Solution Opening the PCAP up in wireshark shows that there are quite a few (37991) DNS packets, as well as a smattring of others (Statistics &amp;gt; Protocol Hierarchy). Let’s look at the remaining packets first, as there are only a few of them:</description></item><item><title>TAMUCTF - WOOF_WOOF</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/tamuctf-woof_woof/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/tamuctf-woof_woof/</guid><description>Prompt (I did not get the prompt text in time, and admin closed access to the challs when the CTF ended :()
The instructions mentioned charset A-Z and ‘-‘ and ‘@’, with flag format GIGEM-....
reveille.png
Solution After running strings on the image to no result, we open this image up in stegsolve, and examine the file format Analyze &amp;gt; File Format. We see the usual stuff, except for:
Comment data Length: 1aa (426) Dump of data: Hex: 01aa776f6f662077 6f6f66206261726b 2072756666206261 726b206261726b20 7275666620776f6f 6620776f6f662062 61726b2072756666 206261726b207275 666620776f6f6620 776f6f6620727566 6620776f6f662062 61726b206261726b 206261726b206261 726b20776f6f6620 7275666620776f6f 66206261726b2062 61726b2072756666 20776f6f6620776f 6f6620776f6f6620 776f6f6620776f6f 6620727566662077 6f6f6620776f6f66 206261726b207275 666620776f6f6620 7275666620626172 6b20776f6f662077 6f6f66206261726b 20776f6f66206261 726b207275666620 6261726b20626172 6b206261726b2072 75666620776f6f66 2072756666206261 726b20776f6f6620 776f6f6620776f6f 6620776f6f662072 75666620776f6f66 206261726b20776f 6f66206261726b20 7275666620626172 6b20776f6f662077 6f6f6620776f6f66 207275666620776f 6f6620776f6f6620 776f6f6620776f6f 6620776f6f662072 75666620776f6f66 206261726b206261 726b206261726b20 7275666620776f6f 66206261726b2062 61726b206261726b 206261726b20776f 6f66 Ascii: .</description></item><item><title>TAMUCTF RSAPWN</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/tamuctf-rsapwn/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/tamuctf-rsapwn/</guid><description>Prompt We must train the next generation of hackers.
nc challenges.tamuctf.com 8573
Solution It looks like this just asks us to find the two “big prime” factors of the number provided, and return them. Athos’ script does exactly that:
python3 ./exploit.py [+] Opening connection to challenges.tamuctf.com on port 8573: Done b&amp;#39;We must train future hackers to break RSA quickly. Here is how this will work.\nI will multiply together two big primes (&amp;lt;= 10000000), give you the result,\nand you must reply to me in less than two seconds telling me what primes I\nmultiplied.</description></item><item><title>VolgaCTF - excellent-crackme</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/volgactf-excellent-crackme/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/volgactf-excellent-crackme/</guid><description>Prompt Excellent Crackme We know one can do pretty much everything in Excel spreadsheets, but this…
excel_crackme
Solution An excel challenge – that’s a first for us! Let’s crack that file open. We used LibreOffice, as Excel was not installed and Libreoffice was. Upon opening, we are greeted with a message that mentions that macros will not be run for security reasons. we’ll look into that in a sec, thank you, LibreOffice.</description></item><item><title>Officer Elections on 3/12</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/officer-elections-on-3-12/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/officer-elections-on-3-12/</guid><description>Next week, we will be having officer elections! This is a great way to get more involved with the club and help represent the College of Engineering. tl;dr Come vote on Thursday, 3/12 at 7pm in KEC 1003. We will have pizza.
I have been the president of the OSU Security Club for nearly 3 years now, and I have loved every second of it. Being able to work with all of you has had a tremendous impact on my college experience, and I thank each and every one of you for contributing to that.</description></item><item><title>Welcome to DamCTF</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/welcome-to-damctf/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/welcome-to-damctf/</guid><description>shamir_babytcache101</description></item><item><title>Meeting Notes 10/3</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-10-3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-10-3/</guid><description>Thanks for the great turnout again tonight! We went over some tools you can use for the NSA Codebreaker challenge.
Here is a link to the slides (requires ONID sign-in): Google Slides
Next week’s CTF meeting is slightly changed, it will be at 7pm in KEC 1003 on Tuesday, 10/8.</description></item><item><title>Meeting Notes 9/26</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-9-26/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-9-26/</guid><description>Thanks everyone for coming out to our first meeting! We had over 50 people in attendance, and introduced the OSU Security Club, what we do, what we stand for, our plans for the year, and worked on a couple introductory CTF challenges.
Here is a link to the slides (requires ONID login): Google Slides
Next week we have two meetings:
The first CTF meeting is Tuesday, 10/1 @ 6:30pm in KEC 1005.</description></item><item><title>NSA Visit</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/nsa-visit/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/nsa-visit/</guid><description>Yesterday the National Security Agency came to meet with some members of the university and give a talk to the OSU Security Club. The visit was a great success and we had over 100 people in attendance for the talk.
The talk was focused around the NSA Codebreaker Challenge, which just started last weekend (Oregon State won last year, and is currently in 2nd place). There was also a long Q&amp;amp;A session following the talk, where club members were able to ask questions about the challenge, in addition to general curiosities about the National Security Agency.</description></item><item><title>DefCon Qualifiers 2019 - redacted-puzzle</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/defcon-qualifiers-2019-redacted-puzzle/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/defcon-qualifiers-2019-redacted-puzzle/</guid><description>The only file given is a GIF image, named redacted-puzzle.gif. We must first inspect it:
$ exiftool redacted-puzzle.gif ExifTool Version Number : 10.80 File Name : redacted-puzzle.gif Directory : . File Size : 78 kB File Modification Date/Time : 2019:05:10 17:05:42-07:00 File Access Date/Time : 2019:05:10 17:05:42-07:00 File Inode Change Date/Time : 2019:05:10 17:26:26-07:00 File Permissions : rwxrwxrwx File Type : GIF File Type Extension : gif MIME Type : image/gif GIF Version : 89a Image Width : 1280 Image Height : 720 Has Color Map : Yes Color Resolution Depth : 3 Bits Per Pixel : 2 Background Color : 3 Animation Iterations : Infinite Frame Count : 35 Duration : 8.</description></item><item><title>Meeting Notes 5/9</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-5-9/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-5-9/</guid><description>Today we hosted Ryan Gurr and Alex Ryan from Fidelis Cybersecurity, who talked about their experiences and background in information security, and showed a cool demo of Fidelis’s platform.
If you have any questions for Ryan or Alex, please contact them, they said they’d love to answer any questions you may have, related to Fidelis or not. You can get their contact info here.</description></item><item><title>2019-2020 Officers</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/2019-2020-officers/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/2019-2020-officers/</guid><description>Here are the new officers for the 2019-2020 school year:
President: Zander Work Vice President: Hadi Rahal-Arabi Treasurer: David Park Multimedia Coordinator: Adam Stewart Lab Manager: Ryan Kennedy Recruitment/Public Relations: Alex Rash Thanks to everyone who participated!</description></item><item><title>ångstromCTF - streams</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/angstromctf-streams/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/angstromctf-streams/</guid><description>Problem White noise is useful whether you are trying to sleep, relaxing, or concentrating on writing papers. Find some natural white noise here.
Note: The flag is all lowercase and follows the standard format (e.g. actf{example_flag})
Author: ctfhaxor
Points: 70
Hint: Are you sure that’s an mp4 file? What’s inside the file?
Solution First, we deduced some information about the challenge by reading the description. “The flag is all lowercase” implies that we will be constructing it letter by letter, possibly from audio.</description></item><item><title>ångstromCTF lithp</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/angstromctf-lithp/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/angstromctf-lithp/</guid><description>Problem My friend gave me this program but I couldn’t understand what he was saying – what was he trying to tell me?
Author: fireholder
Points: 60
Solution First things first, let’s open that lisp program . . . It actually is lisp… oh god what have I just gotten into?
The first lines were most important in solving this challenge the way I did it. It reads:
(defparameter *encrypted* &amp;#39;(8930 15006 8930 10302 11772 13806 13340 11556 12432 13340 10712 10100 11556 12432 9312 10712 10100 10100 8930 10920 8930 5256 9312 9702 8930 10712 15500 9312)) (defparameter *flag* &amp;#39;(redacted)) (defparameter *reorder* &amp;#39;(19 4 14 3 10 17 24 22 8 2 5 11 7 26 0 25 18 6 21 23 9 13 16 1 12 15 27 20)) Well, then.</description></item><item><title>Meeting Notes 4/18</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-4-18/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-4-18/</guid><description>Tonight I gave a tutorial on IDA Pro basics, and how to get started with this awesome tool. I also released some new binaries on the CTF site for you to practice IDA.
Remember, as a OSU Security Club member you have access to our lab systems, which has the full version of IDA Pro and the Hex-Rays Decompiler installed, so make sure to use those if you want to take advantage of the advanced functionality.</description></item><item><title>2019-2020 Officer Elections on April 25th</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/2019-2020-officer-elections-on-april-25th/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/2019-2020-officer-elections-on-april-25th/</guid><description>We will be holding officer elections for next school year during our regular meeting on Week 4 (April 25th). This is a great way to be more involved with the club, and represent us to the College of Engineering.
Here are the positions (link goes to position duties):
President Vice President Treasurer Multimedia Coordinator Lab Manager To run for a position, please do the following:
Fill out this form no later than April 23rd Send a slide (one slide) to security.</description></item><item><title>PRCCDC 2019 Results</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/prccdc-2019-results/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/prccdc-2019-results/</guid><description>This past weekend, OSUSEC competed at the Pacific Rim Collegiate Cyber Defense Competition (PRCCDC) hosted by Highline College. I’m pleased to announce that we placed 3rd out of 13 teams in this tough competition.
PRCCDC is a 2 day competition where each team must secure a mix of approximately 10 Windows and Linux systems, configure a border firewall, monitor and defend against attacks from the Red Team, and work with business users over the phone throughout the event.</description></item><item><title>UTCTF 2019 - Crackme</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/utctf-2019-crackme/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/utctf-2019-crackme/</guid><description>This was a 1200 point reversing challenge (tied for highest point value in the category). Here’s the description:
This what we see when we run the binary:
$ ./crackme Please enter the correct password. &amp;gt;pls Incorrect password. utflag{wrong_password_btw_this_is_not_the_flag_and_if_you_submit_this_i_will_judge_you} Let’s take a look at the code in IDA Pro:
Here’s what the decompilation shows:
Read in 64 bytes from stdin Call divide(32, 0), and save the return value to v4 xor our input at index v4 with 8 Replace a few characters of our input with ‘D’ xor each character in our input with 0x27 Now we see “stuff[j] = stuff2[202 – j] ^ (stuff[j] – 1);”.</description></item><item><title>UTCTF 2019 - Scrambled</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/utctf-2019-scrambled/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/utctf-2019-scrambled/</guid><description>Tl;dr Cool encoding using Rubik’s cube, I wrote a Python script.
This was a 1250 point Forensics challenge (highest points in the category). Here’s the description:
By the time I took a look at the challenge, they had released a hint as well:
Based on the hint, I quickly discovered that the challenge description described ways of manipulating a Rubik’s Cube:
Googling the hint (“rubikstega”) leads to a paper entitled “Rubikstega: A Novel Noiseless Steganography Method in Rubik’s Cube” (link).</description></item><item><title>UTCTF 2019 - Rogue Leader</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/utctf-2019-rogue-leader/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/utctf-2019-rogue-leader/</guid><description>Problem Description Our once-venerable president has committed the unspeakable crime of dine-and-dashing the pizza during our own club meetings. He’s on the run as we speak, but we’re not sure where he’s headed.
Luckily, he forgot that we had planted a packet sniffer on his laptop, and we were able to retrieve the following capture when we raided his apartment: [pcap].
He’s too smart to email his plans to himself, but I’m certain he took them with him somehow.</description></item><item><title>Meeting Notes - 3/7</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-3-7/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-notes-3-7/</guid><description>Thanks to Kees Cook for an awesome look at kernel security! Kees talked about how the kernel exploit for CVE-2017-7038 was discovered, which allowed privilege escalation due to a heap overflow.
You can see his slides here, which also has information for building the POC images for the exploit.
This was our last meeting for Winter 2019, so I’ll see you all next term! Our first meeting will be on Week 2.</description></item><item><title>Meeting 2/28 - OSUSEC Lab</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-2-28-osusec-lab/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-2-28-osusec-lab/</guid><description>Tonight I talked about the new OSUSEC lab environment! A few systems are currently live, and more will be coming up through the end of the term, including the self-registration system. For information about the lab environment, please see the dedicated page for it.</description></item><item><title>Meeting 2/21</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-2-21/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-2-21/</guid><description>Tonight we hosted Karl Fosaaen from NetSPI, and he gave an awesome talk on pentesting in an Azure environment.
If you’re interested in learning more about this, check out the NetSPI blog or the Azure pentesting book he mentioned. Karl’s post on using Azure RunAs certificates is now live here.</description></item><item><title>Meeting 2/14</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-2-14/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-2-14/</guid><description>Tonight I went over some basic usage of GDB, IDA Pro, and pwntools for solving the first pwnables on our CTF site.
Link to the slides (requires ONID login). The slides have information on getting the tools installed, so if you are having issues with that, check the slides out.</description></item><item><title>Meeting 2/7</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-2-7/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-2-7/</guid><description>Today we continued discussing reverse engineering and introduced 64-bit assembly. There are more samples on the GitHub repo.
The only announcement for today is to RSVP for our upcoming event with NetSPI! They will be coming back on 2/21 to do a presentation on penetration testing, and answer any questions you may have. The RSVP is just so I can get a head count for pizza. RSVP here
There are new challenges up on CTFd, rev[1-3]-64.</description></item><item><title>Meeting 1/31</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-1-31/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-1-31/</guid><description>Today we talked about some basic reverse engineering, and compare/contrasting x86 assembly with C code.
There are some new challenges up on CTFd, rev[1-4]
Link to the slides (requires ONID login)</description></item><item><title>Meeting 1/24</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-1-24/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-1-24/</guid><description>Tonight we worked on buffer overflows, and some binaries on the new OSUSEC CTF platform.
Slides (requires ONID login)
Next week, we’re going to work on similar binaries, but comparing the assembly code with the C code.</description></item><item><title>Meeting 1/17</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-1-17/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-1-17/</guid><description>Tonight we talked about some CTF tools and did a walkthrough for “start” on pwnable.tw. You can read a detailed writeup for this binary on the OSUSEC GitHub.
Here’s a link to the slides (requires ONID login): Slides
For those of you who felt lost tonight, my apologies! I received some great feedback, and will have some easier binaries for next week, which will allow me to work on establishing a better baseline for everyone.</description></item><item><title>NSA Codebreaker 2018 - Task 6</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/nsa-codebreaker-2018-task-6/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/nsa-codebreaker-2018-task-6/</guid><description>Loophole – (Smart-Contract Development; Vulnerability Analysis; Exploit Development)
Task 6 has us exploit a loophole in the smart-contracts to recover the decryption key without spending any ether (not including transaction costs). We are given the source for three smart contracts: the Escrow contract, the Ransom contract, and the Registry contract.
Decryption Overview Let’s first look at the intended method of recovering the decryption key.
From the Escrow contract, the victim calls payRansom() to pay the ransom amount.</description></item><item><title>NSA Codebreaker 2018 Task 7</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/nsa-codebreaker-2018-task-7/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/nsa-codebreaker-2018-task-7/</guid><description>Refunds – (Smart-Contract Development; Vulnerability Analysis; Exploit Development)
Task 7 has us refund the victims who have already paid the ransom. In other words, we need to recover all the funds in the Escrow contract, then transfer the funds to the victims. Recall that from task 6, we found that we could deploy and authenticate arbitrary ransom contracts.
Scanning for Vulnerabilities A natural place we can start looking for a vulnerability is the requestRefund() function.</description></item><item><title>Meeting 1/10</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-1-10/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-1-10/</guid><description>Thanks for a great first meeting for Winter 2019!
Here is a link to the slides (requires ONID login): Slides
For those of you who were unable to make it, here’s a brief summary of what we went over. Mostly, it was just talking about what’s coming for the rest of the term:
Updates on the OSUSEC Lab It’s coming. Windows is almost ready and then I’ll be working on Linux.</description></item><item><title>Welcome to Winter 2019!</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/welcome-to-winter-2019/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/welcome-to-winter-2019/</guid><description>Happy New Years! Our first meeting will be this Thursday at 7pm in KEC1003, and we will be meeting at the same time/place the whole term.
Some things to look forward to for this term:
I’m working with NetSPI to have them come back with a more technical presentation and hopefully some labs, so that will be awesome. PRCCDC is in March, with qualifiers in Februrary, so we will be working on putting together a team for that.</description></item><item><title>NSA Codebreaker Challenge 2018 Results</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/nsa-codebreaker-challenge-2018-results/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/nsa-codebreaker-challenge-2018-results/</guid><description>The NSA Codebreaker Challenge finished today, and I’m proud to announce that Oregon State University is the winner! We also had the most people complete Task 5 and 2 people complete Task 7, which is awesome!
For those of you who are unfamiliar with the Codebreaker Challenge, it is a CTF-style event put on every year in the fall by the National Security Agency usually featuring some reverse engineering, vulnerability analysis, and exploit development, along with something unique to keep things interesting.</description></item><item><title>Cyberforce Competition 2018 Results</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/cyberforce-competition-2018-results/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/cyberforce-competition-2018-results/</guid><description>I’m thrilled to announce that OSUSEC placed 1st at the Cyberforce Competition last weekend at PNNL, and 3rd nationwide out of 70 teams! I’m very proud of everyone’s hard work, and am already excited with new ideas for next year. The university is sending out a press release on Thursday so I’ll update this post with a link to that when it comes out.
Link to the competition website: https://cyberforcecompetition.com/</description></item><item><title>Meeting 11/15</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-11-15/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-11-15/</guid><description>Thanks for a great last meeting for the Fall term!
I gave a talk on all of the low-level architecture and x86 assembly content needed to get started with binary pwning, here is a link to the slides. Hopefully, this is enough to get you all started!
Have a great winter break!</description></item><item><title>Meeting 11/01</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-11-01/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-11-01/</guid><description>Thanks to Karl Fosaaen from NetSPI for the awesome presentation on an introduction to penetration testing! Remember, if you want to learn about these things on your own, please make sure to do it on your own network and devices. I’ll update this post with a link to the slides when they become available.
I don’t have any announcements for this week, so I’ll see you all next week!</description></item><item><title>Meeting 10/25</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-10-25/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-10-25/</guid><description>Thanks to Emily for the great talk on SIEMs (Security Incident and Event Management)! Here is a link to the slides.
Announcements from tonight’s meeting:
Make sure to RSVP for the NetSPI event happening next week (during our normal meeting time)! Here is a link to the form. Oct. 25 is the last day to RSVP. Those of you on the team for Cyberforce Competition, make sure to send your badge forms to PNNL.</description></item><item><title>HITCON CTF 2018 EV3 Basic</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/hitcon-ctf-2018-ev3-basic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/hitcon-ctf-2018-ev3-basic/</guid><description>Link to Github
Even though this was a pretty simple challenge, I really enjoyed it and wanted to do a write-up for it anyways.
EV3 is the latest generation of the LEGO Mindstorms robots, and thanks to this challenge I know a lot more about the Mindstorms Communication and Firmware Developer Kits than I ever thought I would.
The challenge includes two files: A picture of the screen of the robot, and a .</description></item><item><title>Meeting 10/11</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-10-11/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-10-11/</guid><description>Thanks Zach for the awesome presentation tonight on Network Security Monitoring! I’ll update this post with a link to the slides once they are available.
Announcements from tonight’s meeting:
Make sure you are on Discord/SLI. Links are on the homepage for those. We will be hosting NetSPI on November 1st. They will be bringing pizza, so please RSVP for this so we can get a head count and information on dietary restrictions.</description></item><item><title>Meeting 10/4</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-10-4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-10-4/</guid><description>Thanks to Akshith for a great presentation on Blockchain! For those of you who were unable to make it, here is a link to the slides: https://drive.google.com/file/d/1-PVTrV6JO6DFnFFz415_JvZ52J-DXJqw/view?usp=sharing
Announcements from today’s meeting:
If you are interested in working in the Information Security Office here at OSU, make sure to apply here: https://jobs.oregonstate.edu/postings/67398. If you have any questions, please contact Emily Longman. No meeting next week (10/11) Applications for Cyberforce Competition will close on October 10th, please fill that out if you are interested: https://goo.</description></item><item><title>Meeting 9/27</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-9-27/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-9-27/</guid><description>Thanks for the awesome turnout tonight! I’ll make a permanent reservation for that space, as it seems like we have a lot more members this year, which is fantastic!
Here is a link to the slides for tonight’s meeting: https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1FyKIu0n8VOtbkOpgnoEFbv3iV2xa7JGM1sUMZdFvLKg/edit?usp=sharing (NOTE: you need to sign in with your OSU account to view them)
Please make sure you register with the club via SLI (Link: https://apps.ideal-logic.com/osusli?key=F3T9-25VWY_5878-CZ4R_bc14da8b).
This weekend we (officers) will be revamping the resources page to provide some guidance for those who are brand new to security and those who have been 1337 pwners for years alike.</description></item><item><title>Cyberforce Competition</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/cyberforce-competition/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/cyberforce-competition/</guid><description>The Cyberforce Competition (formerly known as the Department of Energy Cyber Defense Competition) is coming up in a couple months, and it’s time to start getting ready!
If you are interested in being on the team for this competition, please fill out the form here by October 10th.
Requirements for applying:
You will be able to spend time during October and November preparing for the competition by completing a variety of tasks You are able to travel to Washington or California to compete in the competition on November 30th and December 1st We will probably be leaving the night of the 29th Even if you think you might not be qualified enough, I’d still wholly encourage you to apply.</description></item><item><title>CSAW Prep</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/csaw-prep/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/csaw-prep/</guid><description>It’s time to start getting ready for CSAW CTF!!! If we qualify for the finals, we will send 4 people to New York to compete. The way we will be selecting the four people is as follows:
Register on CSAW 365 (https://365.csaw.io/) Join our class so that I can keep track of your score (Please check Discord or your email for the class code) Work on solving challenges through the end of August.</description></item><item><title>Osusec Wins Department of Energy Cyber Defense Competition</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/osusec-wins-department-of-energy-cyber-defense-competition/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/osusec-wins-department-of-energy-cyber-defense-competition/</guid><description>Over the past weekend, OSUSEC competed in the Department of Energy Cyber Defense Competition (DOE CDC), and placed 1st regionally (US West), and 4th nationwide. The team was responsible for deploying multiple Windows and Linux systems and securing them against live attacks for 8 hours.
The members of the team were:
Zander Work Zach Rogers Cody Holliday Hadi Rahal-Arabi Khuong Luu Aidan Grimshaw Great job guys!</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://osusec.org/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/about/</guid><description>The OSU Security Club was founded in 2014 by Daniel Reichert, and was guided by Dr. Yeongjin Jang until 2023. Currently, the club is advised by Zane Ma. We focus on gaining hands-on experience with exploiting vulnerabilities in systems and networks, defending against these attacks, and getting involved in the security community. There’s no experience or knowledge required, only an interest in learning more about this incredibly important and expanding field!</description></item><item><title>Accomplishments</title><link>https://osusec.org/accomplishments/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/accomplishments/</guid><description>CTFtime Profile
CTF Competitions 12/09/22: 2nd – NSA Codebreaker 10/07/22: 1st – BSides PDX CTF 08/15/22: 16th – DefCon Finals!!! (CTFtime) 05/29/22: 15th – Defcon Qualifiers 04/30/22: 5th – NahamCon CTF 01/04/22: 3rd – NSA Codebreaker (133,337 points) 11/21/21: 5th – N1CTF 10/31/21: 7th – hack.lu CTF 05/02/21: 27th – DefCon Qualifiers 01/31/21: 3rd – NSA Codebreaker 10/23/20: 1st – BSides PDX CTF 05/18/20: 22nd – DefCon Qualifiers (as beaverpwn, in collaboration with RedPwn) 03/22/20: 5th – FireShell CTF 03/15/20: 2nd – b01lers CTF 03/08/20: 5th, 1st university – UTCTF 01/10/20: 3rd – NSA Codebreaker 10/26/19: 1st – BSides PDX CTF 03/10/19: 7th – UTCTF 02/23/19: 3th – MITRE STEM CTF 01/06/19: 1st – NSA Codebreaker CyberDefense Competitions 11/04/23: 15th, 1st regionally - DoE Cyberforce 03/24/23: 1st – PRCCDC 11/05/22: 10th, 1st regionally – DoE Cyberforce 04/23/22: 5th – NCCDC 04/01/22: 1st – PRCCDC 11/13/21: 7th, 1st regionally – DoE Cyberforce 04/11/20: 2nd – PRCCDC 11/16/19: 6th, 1st regionally – DoE Cyberforce 03/24/19: 3rd – PRCCDC 12/01/18: 3rd, 1st regionally – DoE Cyberforce 04/07/18: 4th, 1st regionally – DoE Cyberforce</description></item><item><title>Calendar</title><link>https://osusec.org/calendar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/calendar/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Club Constitution</title><link>https://osusec.org/club-constitution/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/club-constitution/</guid><description/></item><item><title>CTF League</title><link>https://osusec.org/ctf-league/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/ctf-league/</guid><description>Overview The OSUSEC CTF League is a great way for anyone interested in cybersecurity to develop their offensive security skills and get into playing CTF with the OSUSEC team!
CTF League is a year-long competition that runs similar to a standard capture the flag event, with new challenges released every week. Each week, players compete to solve timed challenges intended to teach web, application, and cryptographic security tactics and prepare players for CTF competitions that OSU competes in as a club.</description></item><item><title>Resources</title><link>https://osusec.org/resources/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/resources/</guid><description>Resources List Getting Started
Make sure to sign up for the club on SLI (that’s how we report numbers), and join us on Discord (that’s where all the fun happens). If you play CTF, please join our CTFTime Team!
Main Website: https://www.osusec.org/ Club Constitution: https://www.osusec.org/club-constitution/ Discord: https://discord.gg/2hNARuy CTFTime: https://ctftime.org/team/12858 SLI Signup: https://apps.ideal-logic.com/osusli?key=F3T9-25VWY_5878-CZ4R_bc14da8b Discord Bot Walkthrough: See Below Introductory CTF Material
Interested in getting into Capture The Flag? Check these out! Also join the @CTF role on Discord to participate in CTF with us!</description></item></channel></rss>