<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Club News on OSU Security Club</title><link>https://osusec.org/categories/club-news/</link><description>Recent content in Club News on OSU Security Club</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 09:54:35 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://osusec.org/categories/club-news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Armis Workshop</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/armis-workshop/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 09:54:35 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/armis-workshop/</guid><description>Last Friday night, we were very fortunate to host Terry Boedeker of Armis to discuss IoT security in preparation for Cyberforce next weekend!
He talked about the importance of cyber-physical security and guided us through a hands-on lab with Armis&amp;rsquo; flagship SIEM, tracing exploit attempts and hidden devices on the demo network. It was super valuable and everyone really enjoyed getting to hear this unique industry perspective! We had 28 students come out and participate, and great informal conversations afterward!</description></item><item><title>WWT Blue Team CyberRange</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/wwt-blue-team/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 17:24:37 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/wwt-blue-team/</guid><description>Last Thursday, OSUSEC assembled a team of 4 students to compete in WWT&amp;rsquo;s fantastic blue team CyberRange! We had a ton of fun and are very proud to announce that we placed 3rd, going up against a mixture of teams including those from federal agencies &amp;amp; Fortune 500 companies! We played from 3pm to 3am the next morning, all in one shot. The crash afterwards was not pleasant but it was still worth it &amp;ndash; incident response and cyber competitions take on a wilder and much more creative tone when it&amp;rsquo;s an odd hour in the morning.</description></item><item><title>NCCDC 2023</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/nccdc-2023/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2023 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/nccdc-2023/</guid><description>The last weekend of April, OSUSEC’s Cyber Defense team competed in NCCDC, the National Collegiate Cyber Defense Competition. The competition required us to secure and administer a handful of networks full of virtual machines hosting common business services, as well as continuously respond to IT request tickets and deliver professional reports to supervisors. Students are tested not only on their cybersecurity skills, but also on their time management and interpersonal skills.</description></item><item><title>2023-2024 OSUSEC Officers Selected</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/2023-2024-osusec-officers-selected/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/2023-2024-osusec-officers-selected/</guid><description>This year’s elections were intense; every candidate was subjected to memes, music, and whiteboard art that led to a lot of laughs and a lot of great people elected. Without further adieu, here are your officers for the 2023-2024 academic year:
President: Casey Colley Vice President: Otso Barron Treasurer: Abigail Whittle Lab Manager: Lucas Ball CTF League Coordinator: Zane Othman-Gomez Recruitment and Community Outreach Manager: Julie Weber
Thank you to all who came (or attended on Discord) and took part in democracy!</description></item><item><title>PRCCDC 2023</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/prccdc-2023/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2023 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/prccdc-2023/</guid><description>This past weekend, OSUSEC’s Cyber Defense team competed in PRCCDC, our regional Collegiate Cyber Defense Competition. The competition required us to secure and administer a handful of networks full of virtual machines hosting common business services, as well as continuously respond to IT request tickets and deliver professional reports to supervisors. Students are tested not only on their cybersecurity skills, but also on their time management and interpersonal skills. OSUSEC walked away with 1st place, and will be attending NCCDC (Nationals) at the end of April!</description></item><item><title>Cyberforce Competition 2022</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/cyberforce-competition-2022/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/cyberforce-competition-2022/</guid><description>This past weekend, OSUSEC’s Cyberdefense Competition team flew out to Chicago, IL to compete in the Department of Energy’s Cyberforce Competition! We were tasked with securing and administering a network of 6 virtual machines, then defending it against a team of hackers. Cyberforce also tests students’ abilities to budget their time and respond to miscellaneous requests from managers relating to the NIST framework for cybersecurity. We brought home 10th place out of 169 teams, and placed 1st place for team style 😎</description></item><item><title>BSidesPDX 2022</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/bsidespdx-2022/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/bsidespdx-2022/</guid><description>Howdy Hackers! This Friday, a group of OSUSEC members took a day trip up to Portland to attend BSidesPDX 2022 and compete in their CTF. We had an absolute blast, winning first place in the CTF, attending many interesting talks, and making some new friends! We became known as the team competing in the closet, as the CTF team set up fort in a nearby maintenance closet instead of the official CTF room.</description></item><item><title>2022-2023 OSUSEC Officers Decided</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/2022-2023-osusec-officers-decided/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/2022-2023-osusec-officers-decided/</guid><description>The votes are in! After an entertaining election with some contested positions and contestants running from the floor, the officers for the next academic year, 2022-2023.
President: Cameron McCawley Vice President: Casey Colley Treasurer: Mike Carris Lab Manager: Lucas Ball CTF League Coordinator: Allen Benjamin Recruitment Officer: Brandon Ellis (Interim) Community Manager: Gabriel Kulp
Thanks to everyone who participated!</description></item><item><title>NSA Codebreaker Challenge 2021</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/nsa-codebreaker-challenge-2021/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/nsa-codebreaker-challenge-2021/</guid><description>On January 4th, 2021, OSUSEC finished 3rd place with 133,337 points at the NSA Codebreaker Challenge. 189 OSU students and OSUSEC members solved at least one of the 11 tasks, and 5 OSU students and OSUSEC members solved all 11.
Some more statistics about the competition are below:
Confirmed Public Participants: 5,465 Schools Registered: 631 Task Completions: Task 0: 3,335 Task 1: 2,352 Task 2: 1,385 Task 3: 1,098 Task 4: 778 Task 5: 688 Task 6: 418 Task 7: 196 Task 8: 56 Task 9: 55 Task 10: 42 PCAP Downloads: 3,650 This was a great effort from our team over the course of several months.</description></item><item><title>DOE Cyberforce Competition 2021</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/doe-cyberforce-competition-2021/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Nov 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/doe-cyberforce-competition-2021/</guid><description>On Nov. 13, 2021, the OSUSEC Cyber Defense Competition (CDC) Team placed 1st place regionally and 7th nationwide in the Department of Energy’s annual Cyberforce Competition (https://cyberforcecompetition.com/) out of the 135 teams registered for the competition.
The team roster was:
Casey Colley (Captain) Mike Carris Robert Detjens Brandon Ellis Huy Nguyen Lyell Read The final scoreboard was as follows, if a link to an official final scoreboard is made available, I will link it here.</description></item><item><title>2021-2022 OSUSEC Officers Decided</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/2021-2022-osusec-officers-decided/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/2021-2022-osusec-officers-decided/</guid><description>For the coming school year, we welcome in 8 officers, in the following positions:
President: Lyell Read Vice President: Zach Taylor Treasurer: Mike Carris Lab Manager: Cameron McCawley Community Manager: Christa Wright Recruitment: Brandon Ellis CTF League Coordinator: Allen Benjamin Graphic Designer: Sierra Freihoefer This year is the first year that the posts of Recruitment Officer, CTF League Coordinator, and Community Manager were officially up for grabs. All three were positions that were voted in during the past year by the current officers, to respond to needs for these roles.</description></item><item><title>Thank You</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/thank-you/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/thank-you/</guid><description>Being your club president for the last 3 years has been an incredible experience. Back in Fall 2017 when I first came to OSU, the club had maybe 20-30 members and wasn’t involved in CTF or CDC at all. Now, we’ve reached nearly 300 members, play CTF nearly every weekend, and have many 1st place and top 3 finishes in CDC, not to mention our incredible 1st and 3rd place finishes in the NSA Codebreaker Challenge.</description></item><item><title>PRCCDC 2020 Results</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/prccdc-2020-results/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/prccdc-2020-results/</guid><description>Due to the current COVID-19 pandemic, the in-person Pacific Rim Collegiate Cyber Defense Competition (PRCCDC) was unfortunately cancelled. However, PRCCDC, working in combination with NCCDC, allowed all of the Pacific Rim teams to compete in the National Wildcard Event, which was held online on April 11th, 2020.
I am pleased to announce that OSUSEC placed 2nd in the PRCCDC division (out of 12 teams), and 9th overall (out of 26 teams)!</description></item><item><title>Officer Elections on 3/12</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/officer-elections-on-3-12/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/officer-elections-on-3-12/</guid><description>Next week, we will be having officer elections! This is a great way to get more involved with the club and help represent the College of Engineering. tl;dr Come vote on Thursday, 3/12 at 7pm in KEC 1003. We will have pizza.
I have been the president of the OSU Security Club for nearly 3 years now, and I have loved every second of it. Being able to work with all of you has had a tremendous impact on my college experience, and I thank each and every one of you for contributing to that.</description></item><item><title>NSA Visit</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/nsa-visit/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/nsa-visit/</guid><description>Yesterday the National Security Agency came to meet with some members of the university and give a talk to the OSU Security Club. The visit was a great success and we had over 100 people in attendance for the talk.
The talk was focused around the NSA Codebreaker Challenge, which just started last weekend (Oregon State won last year, and is currently in 2nd place). There was also a long Q&amp;amp;A session following the talk, where club members were able to ask questions about the challenge, in addition to general curiosities about the National Security Agency.</description></item><item><title>2019-2020 Officers</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/2019-2020-officers/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/2019-2020-officers/</guid><description>Here are the new officers for the 2019-2020 school year:
President: Zander Work Vice President: Hadi Rahal-Arabi Treasurer: David Park Multimedia Coordinator: Adam Stewart Lab Manager: Ryan Kennedy Recruitment/Public Relations: Alex Rash Thanks to everyone who participated!</description></item><item><title>2019-2020 Officer Elections on April 25th</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/2019-2020-officer-elections-on-april-25th/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/2019-2020-officer-elections-on-april-25th/</guid><description>We will be holding officer elections for next school year during our regular meeting on Week 4 (April 25th). This is a great way to be more involved with the club, and represent us to the College of Engineering.
Here are the positions (link goes to position duties):
President Vice President Treasurer Multimedia Coordinator Lab Manager To run for a position, please do the following:
Fill out this form no later than April 23rd Send a slide (one slide) to security.</description></item><item><title>PRCCDC 2019 Results</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/prccdc-2019-results/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/prccdc-2019-results/</guid><description>This past weekend, OSUSEC competed at the Pacific Rim Collegiate Cyber Defense Competition (PRCCDC) hosted by Highline College. I’m pleased to announce that we placed 3rd out of 13 teams in this tough competition.
PRCCDC is a 2 day competition where each team must secure a mix of approximately 10 Windows and Linux systems, configure a border firewall, monitor and defend against attacks from the Red Team, and work with business users over the phone throughout the event.</description></item><item><title>Meeting 2/28 - OSUSEC Lab</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-2-28-osusec-lab/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/meeting-2-28-osusec-lab/</guid><description>Tonight I talked about the new OSUSEC lab environment! A few systems are currently live, and more will be coming up through the end of the term, including the self-registration system. For information about the lab environment, please see the dedicated page for it.</description></item><item><title>Welcome to Winter 2019!</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/welcome-to-winter-2019/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/welcome-to-winter-2019/</guid><description>Happy New Years! Our first meeting will be this Thursday at 7pm in KEC1003, and we will be meeting at the same time/place the whole term.
Some things to look forward to for this term:
I’m working with NetSPI to have them come back with a more technical presentation and hopefully some labs, so that will be awesome. PRCCDC is in March, with qualifiers in Februrary, so we will be working on putting together a team for that.</description></item><item><title>NSA Codebreaker Challenge 2018 Results</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/nsa-codebreaker-challenge-2018-results/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/nsa-codebreaker-challenge-2018-results/</guid><description>The NSA Codebreaker Challenge finished today, and I’m proud to announce that Oregon State University is the winner! We also had the most people complete Task 5 and 2 people complete Task 7, which is awesome!
For those of you who are unfamiliar with the Codebreaker Challenge, it is a CTF-style event put on every year in the fall by the National Security Agency usually featuring some reverse engineering, vulnerability analysis, and exploit development, along with something unique to keep things interesting.</description></item><item><title>Cyberforce Competition 2018 Results</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/cyberforce-competition-2018-results/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/cyberforce-competition-2018-results/</guid><description>I’m thrilled to announce that OSUSEC placed 1st at the Cyberforce Competition last weekend at PNNL, and 3rd nationwide out of 70 teams! I’m very proud of everyone’s hard work, and am already excited with new ideas for next year. The university is sending out a press release on Thursday so I’ll update this post with a link to that when it comes out.
Link to the competition website: https://cyberforcecompetition.com/</description></item><item><title>Cyberforce Competition</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/cyberforce-competition/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/cyberforce-competition/</guid><description>The Cyberforce Competition (formerly known as the Department of Energy Cyber Defense Competition) is coming up in a couple months, and it’s time to start getting ready!
If you are interested in being on the team for this competition, please fill out the form here by October 10th.
Requirements for applying:
You will be able to spend time during October and November preparing for the competition by completing a variety of tasks You are able to travel to Washington or California to compete in the competition on November 30th and December 1st We will probably be leaving the night of the 29th Even if you think you might not be qualified enough, I’d still wholly encourage you to apply.</description></item><item><title>CSAW Prep</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/csaw-prep/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/csaw-prep/</guid><description>It’s time to start getting ready for CSAW CTF!!! If we qualify for the finals, we will send 4 people to New York to compete. The way we will be selecting the four people is as follows:
Register on CSAW 365 (https://365.csaw.io/) Join our class so that I can keep track of your score (Please check Discord or your email for the class code) Work on solving challenges through the end of August.</description></item><item><title>Osusec Wins Department of Energy Cyber Defense Competition</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/osusec-wins-department-of-energy-cyber-defense-competition/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/osusec-wins-department-of-energy-cyber-defense-competition/</guid><description>Over the past weekend, OSUSEC competed in the Department of Energy Cyber Defense Competition (DOE CDC), and placed 1st regionally (US West), and 4th nationwide. The team was responsible for deploying multiple Windows and Linux systems and securing them against live attacks for 8 hours.
The members of the team were:
Zander Work Zach Rogers Cody Holliday Hadi Rahal-Arabi Khuong Luu Aidan Grimshaw Great job guys!</description></item></channel></rss>