<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>cyberforce on OSU Security Club</title><link>https://osusec.org/tags/cyberforce/</link><description>Recent content in cyberforce on OSU Security Club</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Nov 2021 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://osusec.org/tags/cyberforce/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>DOE Cyberforce Competition 2021</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/doe-cyberforce-competition-2021/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Nov 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/doe-cyberforce-competition-2021/</guid><description>On Nov. 13, 2021, the OSUSEC Cyber Defense Competition (CDC) Team placed 1st place regionally and 7th nationwide in the Department of Energy’s annual Cyberforce Competition (https://cyberforcecompetition.com/) out of the 135 teams registered for the competition.
The team roster was:
Casey Colley (Captain) Mike Carris Robert Detjens Brandon Ellis Huy Nguyen Lyell Read The final scoreboard was as follows, if a link to an official final scoreboard is made available, I will link it here.</description></item><item><title>Cyberforce Competition</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/cyberforce-competition/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/cyberforce-competition/</guid><description>The Cyberforce Competition (formerly known as the Department of Energy Cyber Defense Competition) is coming up in a couple months, and it’s time to start getting ready!
If you are interested in being on the team for this competition, please fill out the form here by October 10th.
Requirements for applying:
You will be able to spend time during October and November preparing for the competition by completing a variety of tasks You are able to travel to Washington or California to compete in the competition on November 30th and December 1st We will probably be leaving the night of the 29th Even if you think you might not be qualified enough, I’d still wholly encourage you to apply.</description></item></channel></rss>