<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>bsidespdx2020 on OSU Security Club</title><link>https://osusec.org/tags/bsidespdx2020/</link><description>Recent content in bsidespdx2020 on OSU Security Club</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2020 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://osusec.org/tags/bsidespdx2020/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>BSidesPDX - Down the Rabbit Hole</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/bsidespdx-down-the-rabbit-hole/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/bsidespdx-down-the-rabbit-hole/</guid><description>Prompt Category: Over The Air
297 Points
5 Solves
During one of the commercial breaks of my favorite state sponsored educational video, there was some interference once again. There was a woman wearing some sort of face mask and there were strange tones. The tones were familiar and rang a bell, but I couldn’t quite put my finger on them. I don’t know what these things mean, but maybe you can figure it out.</description></item><item><title>BSidesPDX - Please Stand By</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/bsidespdx-please-stand-by/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/bsidespdx-please-stand-by/</guid><description>Prompt Category: Over The Air
263 Points
14 Solves
Sometimes I like to tune into the TV when no shows are on so I can watch the test pattern. I like to believe that there’s a secret message hidden in the transmission.
twitch.tv/over_the_air
Author(s): 0xdade &amp;amp; fdcarl
Solution This challenge is about the “Please Stand By” screen, presumably. Let’s start by looking there. This screen is displayed during the first 2:09 of the twitch stream(recording)</description></item><item><title>BSidesPDX - Xclusive Numborz</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/bsidespdx-xclusive-numborz/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/bsidespdx-xclusive-numborz/</guid><description>Prompt Category: Over The Air
290 Points
8 Solves
I was watching my regularly scheduled state sponsored programming when I got some strange interference. It sounded like a little girl was talking to me but I couldn’t understand what she was saying. Can you figure it out? There’s no space for mistakes, and no room for questions.
twitch.tv/over_the_air
Author(s): 0xdade &amp;amp; fdcarl
Solution The first challenge was easy, but this one is a little trickier.</description></item></channel></rss>