<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>codebreaker on OSU Security Club</title><link>https://osusec.org/tags/codebreaker/</link><description>Recent content in codebreaker on OSU Security Club</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://osusec.org/tags/codebreaker/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>NSA Codebreaker 2018 - Task 6</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/nsa-codebreaker-2018-task-6/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/nsa-codebreaker-2018-task-6/</guid><description>Loophole – (Smart-Contract Development; Vulnerability Analysis; Exploit Development)
Task 6 has us exploit a loophole in the smart-contracts to recover the decryption key without spending any ether (not including transaction costs). We are given the source for three smart contracts: the Escrow contract, the Ransom contract, and the Registry contract.
Decryption Overview Let’s first look at the intended method of recovering the decryption key.
From the Escrow contract, the victim calls payRansom() to pay the ransom amount.</description></item><item><title>NSA Codebreaker 2018 Task 7</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/nsa-codebreaker-2018-task-7/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/nsa-codebreaker-2018-task-7/</guid><description>Refunds – (Smart-Contract Development; Vulnerability Analysis; Exploit Development)
Task 7 has us refund the victims who have already paid the ransom. In other words, we need to recover all the funds in the Escrow contract, then transfer the funds to the victims. Recall that from task 6, we found that we could deploy and authenticate arbitrary ransom contracts.
Scanning for Vulnerabilities A natural place we can start looking for a vulnerability is the requestRefund() function.</description></item><item><title>NSA Codebreaker Challenge 2018 Results</title><link>https://osusec.org/blog/nsa-codebreaker-challenge-2018-results/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://osusec.org/blog/nsa-codebreaker-challenge-2018-results/</guid><description>The NSA Codebreaker Challenge finished today, and I’m proud to announce that Oregon State University is the winner! We also had the most people complete Task 5 and 2 people complete Task 7, which is awesome!
For those of you who are unfamiliar with the Codebreaker Challenge, it is a CTF-style event put on every year in the fall by the National Security Agency usually featuring some reverse engineering, vulnerability analysis, and exploit development, along with something unique to keep things interesting.</description></item></channel></rss>